Okay, good afternoon, good morning or good evening, wherever you are.
好的，下午好，早上好，晚上好，无论你在哪里。
I want to talk today about primary/backup replication,
今天我想谈谈主/备复制，
really sort of an introduction to primary/backup application.
是对主/备应用程序的介绍。
And we'll come back to this in multiple lectures during semester,
我们将在本学期的多节课中讨论这一点，
but this is [] or a VMware fault tolerance paper,
但这是[]或 VMware 容错论文，
is a really nice introduction that brings out a lot of issues,
是一个非常好的介绍，引出了很多问题，
that are gonna come up throughout the semester.
在整个学期都会出现这样的问题。
The plan for lecture today is as follows.
今天课程的计划如下。
I'm just going to talk about failures,
我想谈谈失败，
that you might hope to tolerate using primary/backup replication,
你可能希望使用主/备复制来容错，
and some that you might not be able to.
而有些你可能做不到。
Then I want to talk a little bit about the main challenges,
然后我想谈谈主要挑战，
in sort of any backup scheme,
关于备份的方案，
sort of broad speaking.
从广义上来讲。
Then talk about two you know dominant approaches, two application,
然后谈谈两种主要方法，两种应用，
one is what's typically called state transfer replication,
一种是通常称为状态转移复制，
and the second is typically called replicated state machines.
第二个通常称为复制状态机。
And today's paper is an example of a replicated state machine approach,
今天的论文是复制状态机方法的一个例子，
and if in fact you know lab 2 or lab 3, lab 4
实际上，实验 2 或实验 3 ，实验 4 ，
you know also will be using replicated state machine approach,
也将使用复制状态机方法，
and the fact that the GFS paper is replicating chunks
以及 GFS 论文复制块
was using a replicated state machine approach.
也是使用复制状态机方法。
Since it's quite a common approach.
因为这是一种相当常见的方法。
And then you know what I sort of make everything a little concrete,
然后为了让事情更具体，
by looking at this case the case study,
通过观察这个案例研究，
of the VM VMware fault tolerance scheme or implementation or system.
VMware 容错方案或实施或系统。
Any questions before I get started,
在我开始之前有什么问题吗，
just to,
只是为了，
I have tried to answer all the questions that you send by email,
我试着回答你们通过电子邮件发送的所有问题，
ones you know they're coming before midnight,
在前半夜之前来的，
generally all answer the ones that come in after midnight,
一般都会在后半夜回答，
you know try to answer as many as I can,
尽可能多地回答，
but if I didn't answer your question,
但如果我没有回答你的问题，
then you and the topic comes up at lecture or at any point by the time,
然后，这个话题在上课时或任何时候出现，
you know feel free to interrupt and ask it.
可以随意打断，然后提问。
Okay, any questions, before we dive in.
好了，在我们开始之前，有什么问题吗？
So let's talk about failures in a very broad sense,
所以，让我们从非常广泛的意义上讨论失败，
you get a sense of
你可以大致了解
like what we might hope for that replication scheme can handle.
我们希望复制方案能够处理的（失败）。
So, first of all, the typically,
所以，首先，通常情况下，
the papers that where in the system that we're going to be about building
论文中所要构建的系统，
will only deal with some things
只会处理一些事情，
called were typically called fail-stop failures,
通常称为 fail-stop 失败，
and the basic idea is that,
基本的想法是，
the infrastructure failure
基础设施故障
or component of the computer doesn't really work well,
或计算机组件不能很好地工作，
that actually stops the computer,
使计算机停止运行，
so the assumption is that,
所以假设是，
basically the computer goes from working to not working, so instantaneously,
计算机瞬间从工作到不工作，
it doesn't produce like weird results,
它不会产生奇怪的结果，
because the computer is not working, correctly.
因为计算机不能正常工作。
So it just follows the protocols,
所以跟据这个协议，
you know when does to adds it to register values,
当你对寄存器值相加，
you know that produces are correct, add value,
它会产生相加值，
and so we're just assuming that,
所以我们假设，
when the computer works, it works correctly,
当计算机工作时，它就会正确工作，
and when there's a failure, it just stops.
当有失败的时候，它就会停止。
This covers in many scenarios,
这会包括许多情况，
for example whatever you know fan of the computer fails,
比如，无论计算机风扇出现故障，
you know the computer overheat,
计算机过热，
and then the computer shuts down itself,
然后计算机自动关机，
the other cases are where somebody steps over the power cord,
其他情况是有人跨过电源线，
and boom, you know the whole computer disappears,
然后突然，整个电脑都消失了，
or you know cuts the network link,
或者切断网络连接，
and at that point,
在这个时刻，
you know the computer by keeping running
计算机保持运行，
about is completely disconnected.
但完全断开了连接。
Sometimes you know systems or software on the computer itself,
有时计算机本身的系统或软件，
it does best you know to turn these partial failures into a stop fail-stop failures,
最好的做法是将部分故障转变为 fail-stop 失败，
for example you might software might compute checksums on data,
例如，软件计算数据的校验和，
and then if it sees that the checksum is incorrect,
然后，如果它发现校验和不正确，
you know just stop you know the computer.
可以直接停止计算机。
And so those are quite common
所以这些都是很常见的，
and to do so,
要做到这一点，
the basic model of the word is,
这个词的意思是，
computer work correctly, then the computer stops.
计算机正常工作，然后计算停止。
So what does this exclude,
那么，这排除了什么，
you know there's a whole bunch of sort of failures that exclude,
有一大堆的失败被排除了，
for example it doesn't really deal well with logic bugs,
例如，它不能很好地处理逻辑错误，
like if you have an error in your software,
比如，如果你的软件有错误，
you know whatever you divide by zero
无论你除以零，
and incorrectly you were where you shouldn't have,
或者你不应该有的错误，
then you know it is very likely,
然后非常可能，
that the backup will do exactly the same thing,
备份也会做同样的事情，
because one of the software which is broken,
因为其中一个软件是坏的，
and so it's broken on the primary, it's broken on the backup,
所以，它在主机上出现故障，也在备份机上出现故障，
and so nothing you know basically replication really not
所以，复制不能
does not solve that problem for you.
不能为你解决这类问题。
Similar, if you have configuration errors,
类似地，如果你有配置错误，
primary/backup is not going to solve you the problem for you,
主/备不会为你解决这类问题，
if you know the, the files that you specify the replica said that incorrect,
如果你指定的文件，复制说不正确，
then the system will not work correctly.
那么系统将不能正常工作。
Similarly, we're not really in this class,
同样，我们不在这节课上，
we'll talk a little bit at the end of the semester,
我们会在学期末讨论，
but we're not dealing with malicious errors,
但我们不能处理恶意错误，
so we're not dealing with attackers you know try to fake the protocol,
所以不能处理试图伪造协议的攻击者，
you know have run servers that send incorrect messages
运行服务器发送错误消息，
and try to sort of spoof the whole system,
并试图戏弄整个系统，
we're just not in consideration.
这不在我们考虑之列。
So in the for most of the semester,
所以在这学期的大部分时间里，
we assume that the software works correctly,
我们假设软件工作正常，
does not have logic bugs,
没有逻辑错误，
that no configuration errors,
没有配置错误，
and the thing that we're focusing on is actually handling stop failures.
我们关注的事情是处理停止失败。
There's some failures that sort of fail,
有一些失败，
that could be handled or may be handled with primary/backup replication
是可以使用主备复制处理的，
or or not,
或者不可以，
as an example, you might think about an earthquake,
比如，你可能会想到地震，
you know if the primary/backup are physically you know separated,
如果主备在物理上是分开的，
in completely different parts,
在完全不同的地方，
you know different continents or different parts of the same continent,
在不同的大陆或同一大陆的不同部分，
when that, you might hope that,
在这种情况下，你可能会希望，
you might have some hope that,
你可能会希望，
the backup could take over,
备机可以接管，
if the primary fails due to an earthquake,
如果主机因为地震发生故障，
but you know some other primary replication schemes,
但是其他一些复制方案，
this is not going to be the case,
情况不会是这样的，
you know [] primary and the backup on the same data center,
主备在同一个数据中心，
and the whole data center disappears,
整个数据中心都会消失，
then you know sort of end of story.
那么故事就结束了。
Okay?
好的?
So hopefully that gives you a little bit of context
希望这能给你一些背景知识，
of the type of failures you're trying to shoot for.
关于你试图解决的失败类型。
You know, even with this sort of just focusing on stop fail-stop failures,
即使只关注 fail-stop 故障，
that turns out to be difficult to build fault tolerant systems,
也很难建立容错系统，
we're going to talk a little bit about the general issues that will show up,
我们将讨论一下会出现的一般性问题，
you know if we're going to build a primary/backup system,
如果我们要建立一个主备系统，
and also concrete instances of these problems in in the the VM FT paper.
在 VM FT 论文中有具体的这些问题。
So you know one challenge is
所以一个挑战是，
you know if a failure happens,
如果失败发生，
you know has the primary actually failed?
主机真的失败了吗？
A issue here you know that makes this challenging is that,
让这件事变得具有挑战性的一个问题是，
in distributed systems,
在分布式系统中，
you can't tell the difference between a network partition and a machine failed,
你无法区分网络分区和机器故障，
so it might be perfectly possible,
所以完全有可能，
that the network, that the primary is still up,
网络， primary 还在运行，初选还在继续，
but you know that some computers cannot talk to the primary,
但是有些计算机不能与 primary 交互，
because the network has partitioned,
因为网络已经分区，
and so for example the backup might decide,
比如， backup 可能会决定，
that you know the primary is dead,
primary 已经失效，
because networks partitioned,
因为网络分区，
but in fact the primary is not that,
但是实际上 primary 并没有，
maybe some of the clients are still able to talk to the primary,
也许有些客户端还能访问 primary ，
so you have to have some story
所以你必须有一些[故事]
of making sure that you don't end up in a situation where you have two primaries.
来确保你不会陷入有两个 primary 的情况。
And again, you know we talked a little bit about last time,
同样地，我们上一次讨论了，
it shows up in this paper again,
它再次出现在这篇论文中，
will show up next week too,
下周也会出现，
which is like we want to avoid that we get into a situation,
我们想要避免陷入这样的境地，
where there's a split-brain system,
有一个脑裂系统，
where we basically have two primaries,
我们有两个 primary ，
and one subset of client talks to one primary,
一个客户端子集访问一个 primary ，
and the other subset of client talks to the other primary,
另一个客户端子集访问另一个 primary ，
and clearly that's going to diverge you know the state of the system
很明显这会产生系统状态的分歧，
and when the network heals, we are in an incorrect state,
当网络恢复时，我们处于错误的状态，
so we have to avoid this at all cost.
所以，我们必须不惜一切代价避免这种情况。
The second general challenge is,
第二个挑战是，
how do we keep the,
我们如何才能保持，
you know how do we keep the primary/backup in sync.
如何使主备保持同步。
Our goal is going to be that,
我们的目标是，
if the primary fails,
如果 primary 出现故障，
then we can just gracefully fail over to backup,
然后，我们可以正常地切换到 backup ，
and the backup just picks up right where the primary left off,
backup 在 primary 停止的地方重新开始，
that requires that the backup actually is up to date,
这要求 backup 总是最新的，
like the latest things that are primary actually has written to its state,
有 primary 已经写入的最新状态，
so that actually can pick up seamlessly
以便操作可以无缝进行，
and don't return errors or responses to the client to completely unexpected,
而不会向客户端返回错误或无法响应，
from the client's perspective,
从客户的角度来看，
really what should look like,
真正看起来，
you know the whole thing even though it's replicated,
即使它是复制的，
like a single computer,
就像一台计算机，
just happens to be a little more fault tolerant than a single computer.
只是比一台计算机具有更强的容错能力。
And that turns out to be difficult,
事实证明，这是困难的，
you know first of all,
首先，
we have to make sure that we apply all changes,
我们必须确保我们应用所有的变更，
we have to apply the changes in the right order,
我们必须按正确的顺序应用变更，
and you know in continuous issue in that,
在连续性问题中，
we have to sort of avoid non-determinism,
我们必须避免非决定论，
or we have to deal with non-determinism,
或者我们必须解决非决定论，
I mean the same change on the primary behaves different on the backup,
我的意思是，相同的更改在 primary 的行为与在 backup 上的不同，
because for some reason, that would be not good,
因为出于某种原因，这样并不好，
you know we got to make sure,
我们必须确保，
that we make a change in the primary/backup
我们在主备上做的变更，
very identical effects to the primary/backup.
对主备有完全相同的作用。
A similar issue that always shows up,
一个经常出现的问题，
you know challenge is fail over,
一个挑战就是故障转移，
you have actually the primary fails,
你的主机出现故障，
and we need to fail over to the backup,
我们需要切换到备机，
and of course we've got to make sure that,
当然我们必须确保，
there are other primary is definitely dead,
其他主机已经停机，
but for example the primary might have was in the middle of an operation,
但是，比如主机可能在操作过程中，
and it was about to send a packet out,
它即将发送一个数据包，
to the response to the client,
对客户端进行回复，
or maybe not,
也可能不是，
and so we got to figure out,
所以我们要弄清楚，
what that response that being send or not being sent,
响应已经发送或没有发送，
or is it okay for us to send it again.
或者我们可以再发一次。
There's a question in the chat,
聊天中有一个问题，
like when would fail over need to happen,
什么时候需要进行故障转移，
you know fail over need to happen when the primary is gone, right,
当主机停机后需要故障转移，
because then we want to fail over to the backup,
因为我们想要故障转移到备机，
that determine all you used.
这取决于你的使用。
And then often another issue we fail over is,
然后，另一个故障转移的问题是，
who actually has to know we have multiple backups,
我们有多个备份，
which is not the case in today's paper,
不是今天论文中的情况，
yeah we actually ask the latest [stage],
是的，我们要问的是最新的[阶段]，
like for example, maybe they all crash after a few operations,
比如，可能在一些操作后，它们都会崩溃，
they come back up
它们回来，
and and and we're going to make sure that,
我们要确保，
we're actually talking to one that has the most recent states,
我们与有最新的状态服务器交互，
this is going to not an issue today so much,
这不是今天的一个问题，
as we'll see in a second why,
我们稍后会知道为什么，
but we'll come up later in other replication protocols.
但我们之后会在其他复制协议中介绍。
Yeah, so basically fail over means the backup takes over.
是的，所以故障转移意味着备机接管。
Okay, so that's sort of the main you know failure,
好的，这就是主要失败，
the type of failures that we hope to handle and the main challenges,
我们希望处理的失败类型和主要挑战，
in we'll deepen those challenges out as we go.
随着我们继续，将会深入讨论这些挑战。
You know I want to talk about two two main approaches,
我想谈谈两种主要的方法，
that we'll see in a semester,
我们将在一个学期内看到，
for dealing with primary/backup replication.
用于处理主备复制。
One is as I mentioned earlier, that is state transfer,
一个是我前面提到的状态转移，
you know these reasonable at a high-level very straightforward,
这些从高层来说是非常直截了当的，
you know we've got a primary,
我们有主机，
you know if you know the clients talk to the primary,
如果客户端与主机交互，
and the primary updated state,
主机更新状态，
once updated state in response to client request,
响应于客户端请求而更新状态，
and once a while, it sort of makes checkpoint,
每隔一段时间，会有一个检查点，
once a while, basically checkpoints state, it's state to the backup,
每隔一段时间，检查点将状态给备机，
and of course if we want the backup and the primary to be in sync,
当然，如果我们希望备机和主机同步，
that means that every time the primary actually performs the operation,
这意味着每次主机执行操作，
before it responds to the client,
在响应客户端之前，
it basically has to transfer whatever state changes that were made by the operation to the backup.
它必须传输操作所做的状态变更到备机。
So that's one scheme.
所以这是一个方案。
One of high-level approach, second approach is,
另一种高级别的方法，第二种方法是，
what is called replicated state machine, state machine replication,
称为复制状态机，状态机复制，
often shortened to RSM.
通常简称为 RSM 。
And here you know the you know the picture is,
在这里，图片是，
we still got the primary,
我们仍然有主机，
we've got the client talking to the primary,
我们有客户端访问主机，
and of course we have the primary talking to backup
当然，我们有主机与备机交互，
to keep the backup in sync,
以保持备备机同步，
but instead it sending the state changes or modifications to the state
但是不是发送状态变更，
from the primary to the backup,
从主机到备机，
but we do actually sent the operations to the backup,
而是发送操作给备机，
so before the primary response to the client,
所以，在主机响应客户端之前，
you know executing its operation,
执行它的操作，
we sent the operation that the client sent to us to the backup,
我们将客户端发送给我们的操作发送给备机，
the backup can execute the operation too,
备机也可以执行操作，
updated state, acknowledge it to the primary,
更新状态，向主机确认，
primary actually updates its state too,
主机也更新它的状态，
you know execute the operation,
执行操作，
and then sends a response back to the client.
然后将响应发送回客户端。
And so in all these sort of, in all these both approaches,
所以在所有这两种方法中，
you know the scheme is the primary of some particular state,
计划是主机有一些状态，
we apply changes to the state,
我们应用变更到这些状态，
and we do exactly the same thing as the backup,
我们对备机做完全相同的操作，
so the backup system starts out in the same state as the primary,
备机与主机有相同的开始状态，
we apply the same changes to the state,
我们将同样的变更应用于状态，
where it's through an operation state transfer,
通过操作状态转移，
we end up in a new state,
我们最终进入了一个新的状态，
and that state has to be identical to the state that the primary has.
并且该状态必须与主机的状态相同。
And so even ever there's a failure,
所以，如果失败了，
you know, we know that when we fail over to backup,
我们故障切换到备份时，
and it's exactly the same state as the primary,
它与主机的状态完全相同，
and so it can take over.
所以，它可以接管。
We'll see you know this is actually challenging to actually make happen,
我们会看到这是一种挑战，
but that's the basic plan,
但这是基本的计划，
the primary both approach is actually reasonable popular,
两种方法都是很受欢迎的，
the primary disadvantages, the state transfer approach is that,
状态转移方法的主要缺点是，
if an operation generates a lot of state,
如果一个操作生成很多状态，
then it's going to be expensive,
那就会很昂贵了，
for a single operation writes gigabyte of data,
对于单个操作写入千兆字节的数据，
then gigabyte of data needs to be transferred to the primary to the backup,
然后千兆字节的数据需要传输到备机，
and it might be much more expensive, much more, less expensive
而且它可能要昂贵得多，便宜得多，
to basically just send over the operation to the backups,
只把操作发送给备机，
backup can executing operation.
备机就可以执行操作。
So many of the systems that we're talking about,
我们讨论的许多系统，
actually they're follow the second approach
它们使用第二种方法，
where they send the operation, but not the state transfer.
它们发送操作，而不是状态转移。
And in fact if you think about GFS,
事实上，如果你想一想 GFS ，
the discussion from last week,
上周讨论的，
when we just saw that,
我们可以看到，
basically the primary sends the append operations or the write operations to the backups,
主机发送追加操作或写入操作给备机，
doesn't do the append and then send the result to the backups,
不是执行追加操作，然后将结果发送到备机，
that actually sends the operations,
它实际上发送操作，
so that's an example of a replicated state machine approach,
所以这是复制状态机方法的一个示例，
where we'll be sending operations.
我们将发送操作。
And the paper of today also follows this replicated state machine approach,
今天的论文也遵循了复制状态机的方法，
where the operations are not you know append and write,
操作不是追加和写入，
file system append, file system write,
文件系统附加，文件系统写入，
but the operations are actually x86 instructions,
而是这些操作是 x86 指令，
you know we'll see later,
我们稍后会看到，
but they both you know send operations.
但它们都是发送操作。
In labs, as I mentioned earlier,
在实验中，正如我前面提到的，
lab 3 and 4 are also a replicated state machine approach,
实验 3 和实验 4 也是复制状态机方法，
where we're gonna be sending operations from primary to backup.
我们发送操作从主机到备机。
As a.
作为。
Okay, there's a question in chat,
聊天中有个问题，
why does the client do not send not need to send the data to backup
为什么客户端不需要发送数据给备机，
in our replication state machine,
在我们的复制状态机中，
because the the idea is that these operations are deterministic,
因为这个想法是这些操作是确定性的，
and so the primary and this you know remember,
所以主机，你记得，
we'll talk about this in much more detail,
我们会更详细地讨论这个，
but the primary/backup are in the same state,
但是主备处于相同的状态，
same state as the,
相同的状态，
if the operation is deterministic,
如果操作是确定性的，
and you apply it to the same state,
你把它应用于相同的状态，
you know they will end up in the same state as primary,
它们最终会和主机处于相同的状态，
and so there's no reason for the application, the client to send the data,
所以，应用程序、客户端没有理由发送数据，
in this case,
在这种情况下，
because by just sending this deterministic operation,
因为只要发送这个确定性的操作，
it is guaranteed,
就可以保证，
that operation will generate the same data.
操作将生成相同的数据。
So subsequent question is,
所以接下来的问题是，
how do you know for all programs and their operations,
怎么知道所有程序和操作，
whether they are deterministic or non-deterministic,
它们是确定性的还是非确定性的，
to know what information needs to be sent.
知道需要发送哪些信息。
So the typical approaches do in a replicated state machine approach is
所以在复制状态机方法中的典型做法是，
to make all operations deterministic,
使所有操作都是确定性的，
non-deterministic operations are not allowed,
不允许非确定性操作，
and we'll see in a second how to do that.
我们很快会看到如何做到这个。
Okay, so before you know go into a little bit more specific,
好的，在你知道更多细节之前，
and a hybrid approach,
有一种混合方法，
yes you know there a hybrid approach,
是的，有一种混合方法，
you know for example you can run sort of
例如，你可以运行
by default in a replicated state machine approach,
默认情况下以复制状态机方法，
in the fact, so in some ways the paper does this,
实际上，这篇论文在某些方面做了这一点，
then if a backup fails or primary fails,
如果备机失败或主机失败，
and you go back to a single machine,
你回到一台单独的机器，
then you need to create a new replica,
然后，你需要创建一个新副本，
and often new replica the way you do,
通常对于你创建的新副本，
it is actually by transferring the state from the existing replica
它是通过转移现有副本的状态，
or copy of the state of existing replica to the new replica,
或复制现有副本的状态到新的副本，
without like hopefully less frequent operation.
不是那么频繁的操作。
And then actually you know during,
然后在，
then replicating the operations you're doing much more frequently.
然后频繁地复制你正在做的操作。
Also free, feel free to ask questions in real time
同时可以实时自由地提问，
as opposed to typing in the chat,
而不是在聊天中打字，
either way is fine, but.
哪种方式都可以，但是。
Okay, so, as I hinted,
好的，正如我提到的，
you know with this replicated state machine approach,
使用这种复制状态机方法，
there's a question about
有一个问题，
what level of replication are doing
执行什么级别的复制，
or what level of operations to replicate.
或要复制什么级别的操作。
So one one of possibilities sort of application level operations,
一种可能是应用程序级别的操作，
so what I mean is,
所以我的意思是，
you know think back GFS,
回想一下 GFS ，
like whether it's append file append or write.
比如它的文件追加或写入。
Another and okay and
另一方面，好的，
if you play a game sort of replicate state machine game
如果你玩一个复制状态机的游戏，
at the level of these application level operations,
在应用程序级别的操作上，
that means that the application has to be involved,
这意味着必须涉及到应用程序，
because it knows what the semantics of these operations are,
因为它知道这些操作的语义是什么。
and then it knows what append actually supposed to do,
它知道追加实际应该做什么，
or what write you're supposed to do,
或者写入应该做什么，
and so, if you're playing a replicated state machine approach
所以，如果你使用复制状态机方法，
at that kind of application level,
在应用程序级别，
then the application itself needs to be modified
那么需要修改应用程序本身
to actually perform or play part of the replicated state machine approach.
以执行或作为复制状态机方法的一部分。
One thing that's cool about the paper today that we're looking at to,
今天我们看的论文，有一件很酷的事情，
it's like looking at today is,
今天看的是，
it you know operations at the machine level,
在机器层面的操作，
or the processor level or computer level,
或处理器级别或计算机级别，
and so the state is registers x86 registers, the memory state,
所以状态是 x86 寄存器，内存状态，
and the operations are just an ordinary computer instructions
操作是传统的计算机指令，
and by replicating at that level,
通过在这个级别进行复制，
then you can basically make your application completely transparent,
可以使你的应用程序完全透明，
because you can take one computer,
因为你可以使用一台计算机，
run the application operating system on top of it,
在它上面运行应用程序和操作系统，
just runs x86 instructions,
只是运行 x86 指令，
and this replicated state machine approach
并且这个复制状态机方法
automatically creates backup of that particular execution,
自动创建特定执行的备份，
so the application doesn't have to be modified at all,
所以应用程序根本不需要修改，
in fact, in this paper, the operating system is not modified,
实际上，在这个论文中，操作系统并没有被修改，
the application is not modified,
应用程序没有被修改，
you can take an ordinary application,
你可以使用普通的应用程序，
not even written with fault tolerance in mind,
甚至在编写时都不用考虑容错，
and using this sort of machine level or instruction level replication,
使用这种机器级或指令级复制，
it can be transparently replicated.
它可以透明地复制。
One of the things that's very cool
一件非常酷的事情，
about you know paper of today is completely transparent.
关于今天的论文，它是完全透明的。
You know that makes you wonder you know how to do that,
这让你想知道怎么去做，
because what happens,
因为会发生什么，
if you look at machine
如果你查看机器，
and an interrupt happens,
一个中断发生，
you know that interrupt needs to be propagated in some way directly to the backup,
那个中断需要以某种方式直接传播到备份，
because like if you think about the x86 machine,
因为如果你考虑 x86 机器，
of course the regular instructions that the applications execute,
当然，应用程序执行的常规指令，
like add, you know whatever divide, you know conditional branch branching procedure calls,
比如加法，除法，条件分支过程调用，
but there are also other events like an interrupts,
但是还有其他事件，比如中断，
and they need to be you know handled with,
它们也需要被处理，
so how do you do that.
那么你如何做到这个。
And so a traditional, a way of doing a machine level replication,
所以，一种传统的进行机器级别复制的方式，
used to be sort of quite expensive,
使用起来相当昂贵，
in the sense that,
从某种意义上说，
the you could buy computers or whatever processors,
你可以购买计算机或者处理器，
like maybe replicated twice or three times
可能复制两到三次，
and the hardware itself would organize you know these processors
硬件本身会组织这些处理器，
sort of ran exactly in lockstep,
完全同步地运行，
and you know there's a lot of hardware machinery to actually make this happen,
有很多硬件设备可以实现这一点，
and this paper has a cool observation that,
这篇论文有一个很酷的观察，
you don't really need to do really hardware replication,
你并不需要进行真正的硬件复制，
instead you can actually use virtual machines,
相反，你可以使用虚拟机，
and that's the way they do it,
这就是他们的做法，
that pure hardware replication happens too,
纯硬件复制也会发生，
you know, for example in in [] or whatever [] over,
例如，在[]或[]中，
you know often the hardware modules are just like
硬件模块通常是
duplex replicated to triple replication
双重复制或三重复制，
and have a hardware voting scheme
并且有使硬件表决方案，
to keep the processors in sync to detect failures,
使处理器保持同步以检测故障，
but that sort of level of fault tolerance,
但是这种级别的容错，
that is not the the level, is that VM-FT paper not actually shooting for,
不是 VM-FT 论文所讨论的级别，
is really thinking about like,
考虑一下，
you know you got in a business application running on on the computer,
你在计算机上运行商业应用程序，
and now you want to make that business application more fault tolerant,
你希望使业务应用程序具有更强的容错能力，
and the approach to take is to exploit virtualization.
而采取的方法是利用虚拟化。
So the situation to VM-FT is exploit virtualization,
所以， VM-FT 的情况是利用虚拟化，
that's the main big idea,
这是主要的想法，
that they bring along to this problem,
他们为解决这个问题而提出的，
and you know by doing so,
通过这样做，
they can make this replication transparent to the application,
他们可以使复制对应用程序透明。
of course, you don't have to design,
当然，你不需要设计，
as an application design and then the replication scheme,
比如应用程序的复制方案，
where like for example the way it's done in, in GFS,
例如在 GFS 中的复制方式，
it appears using the scheme,
使用这个方案，
this replication scheme that VM-FT uses,
VM-FT 使用的复制方案，
appears basically that the appears to client,
呈现给客户端，
but the server is a single machine,
服务器是单独一台机器，
meaning just you know seeing in a second how,
意思是，我们稍后会看到是怎么回事，
but basically they're gonna provide very strong consistency,
但它们会提供非常强的一致性，
you know the client on the outside can't even tell.
外部的客户端甚至看不出来。
And, it actually you know the paper sort of cool paper,
而且，这篇论文是很酷的论文，
because it actually is, it's a real product,
因为它是一个真正的产品，
and it's still in use,
而且它还在使用中，
you know you can get this, there's this support if you want to.
如果你愿意的话，可以获得这种支持。
The current product I think is quite different from the one,
我认为目前的产品有些不同，
that we actually read about in the paper,
与我们在论文上看到的，
but you know at a very high level,
但是在高的级别上，
you know the issues are very similar,
这些问题非常相似，
in fact you know one of the big shortcomings
事实上，最大的缺点之一，
as many of you noted in the questions,
就像你们中的许多人在问题中指出的那样，
of the the one that [] in the paper,
论文中的一个[]，
it's a single core solution,
这是一个单核心解决方案，
so there's no multi-core support,
所以不存在多核支持，
so multiple applications or multiple threads on one computer cannot run in parallel,
所以一台计算机上的多个程序或多个线程不能并行运行，
then we'll talk about in a second,
稍后我们将会讨论，
why this solution doesn't really support that,
为什么这个解决方案不支持，
in I think later later versions of FT does actually works,
我想后来的 FT 版本可以支持，
and I think there's no paper detail paper that describes it,
但是没有论文详细描述它，
but I actually think that,
但是我认为，
instead of using actually replicated state machine approach,
不是使用复制状态机方法，
actually using state transfer approach,
而是使用状态转移方法，
but I really don't know any really the details.
但是我也不知道任何细节。
We're going to focus on the replicated state machine approach,
我们将重点介绍复制状态机方法，
because one reason I like this paper is,
因为我喜欢这篇论文的一个原因是，
because it sort of illustrates replicated state machine approach in a very clean manner,
因为它以一种非常清晰的方式说明了复制状态机方法，
and all the you know all the subsequent replication schemes,
所有后续的复制方案，
that were going to be looking at
我们要看的（复制方案）
are replicated state machine approaches.
都是复制状态机方法。
Okay, so, so let's sketch out the overview of the system.
好的，让我们来描述这个系统的概况。
And so the first thing sort of need to realizes that,
所以首先要注意的是，
there's a virtual virtual machine monitor involved,
有一个虚拟机监控器，
so what is a virtual machine monitor,
那么什么是虚拟机监控器，
well virtual machine monitor basically takes a piece of hardware
虚拟机监控器使用一块硬件，
and it makes it appear you know basically makes n pieces of hardware out of it.
并产生 n 块硬件，
So if we look at the x86 box,
如果我们看一下 x86 盒子，
you know we can take a virtual machine monitor run it on top of it,
我们可以在它上面运行一个虚拟机监视器，
and you know on top of it, we can have virtual machines,
在它之上，我们可以有虚拟机，
and virtual machine, we're gonna have multiple virtual machines,
我们有多个虚拟机，
although most of this paper we're going to be talking about,
尽管篇论文的大部分内容我们讨论的是，
running one virtual machine on top of the virtual machine monitor.
在虚拟机监视器之上运行一个虚拟机。
And so for example we might actually have a Linux operating system
例如，我们可能有一个 Linux 操作系统
running on top of the virtual machine with its applications.
和它的应用程序一起运行在虚拟机上。
And you know here is actually the actual hardware.
这里是实际的硬件。
And why you know so and so VM,
为什么虚拟机，
the terminology used here sometimes called a hypervisor,
这里使用的术语有时称为 hypervisor ，
it's called a virtual machine monitor,
它被称为虚拟机监控器，
and so in our case, you know will the the hypervisor here,
在我们的例子中，这里的虚拟机监视器，
this is actually you know VM-FT,
实际上就是 VM-FT ，
so it's a hypervisor modified,
它是经过修改的虚拟机监视器程序，
you know to include you know the ideas that were VM-FT has.
包括 VM-FT 的想法。
Why is this cool,
为什么这很酷，
well, the reason this is cool, because,
这很酷的原因是，
or useful for replicated state machines is,
或者对复制状态机很有用的原因是，
because even a hardware interrupt actually happens,
因为即使一个硬件中断发生，
that hardware interrupt doesn't really go straight to Linux,
硬件中断不会直接到 Linux ，
in fact, the hardware interrupt goes first through the VM monitor,
事实上，硬件中断首先通过虚拟机监视器，
the VM monitor actually decides
虚拟机监视器决定
you know when to deliver you know that interrupt to Linux.
什么时候将中断传递给 Linux 。
And so any external events before they actually sort of observed by the virtual machines
所以，任何外部事件在被虚拟机观察到之前，
actually captured by or can be captured by the hypervisor.
可以由虚拟机监视器捕获。
And so this gets us out of this mess,
所以这让我们摆脱了这个困境，
you know like what I mentioned a bit earlier,
就像我刚才提到的，
where you know what happens if there's an external interrupt,
如果有外部中断会发生什么，
how can we replicate that,
我们如何才能复制它，
and the way we're going to replicate here is,
我们要在这里复制的方式是，
because the virtual machine monitor just get control over it.
因为虚拟机监视器会控制它。
And we'll see you know there's going to be an extremely powerful tool
我们会看到一个非常强大的工具
to actually make instruction deterministic,
真正使指令具有确定性，
you know handle external operations, etc etc.
处理外部操作，等等。
So the basic plan is,
所以基本的计划是，
like if an interrupt comes in,
如果出现中断，
you know where there's an interrupt from the network
无论是从网络来的中断，
or from from the hardware itself, like a timer interrupt,
或者来自硬件本身，比如定时器中断，
you know basically the timer interrupt is delivered to the virtual machine monitor,
基本上定时器中断被传送到虚拟机监视器，
virtual machine monitor, then in the case of VMFT, does two things,
然后在 VM-FT 的情况下，虚拟机监视器会做两件事，
you know not only delivers it at some point to the application,
不仅会在某个时刻把它传递给应用程序，
it also sends it over a logging channel to a backup computer,
它还通过日志通道将其发送到备份计算机，
backup computer is constructed in the same way as hardware,
备份计算机与硬件相同的方式构建，
it has virtual machine monitor sitting on top of it,
它有一个虚拟机监视器，
so there's another copy of VM-FT,
所以还有另一个 VM-FT ，
and on top of is a virtual machine,
在它上面是一台虚拟机，
were identical software running on it like Linux,
是运行的确定的软件，比如 Linux ，
same version of Linux,
相同版本的 Linux ，
you know with whatever some set of applications.
以及不管什么应用程序。
Okay?
好的?
And so like you know these machines both on networks use the logging channel,
如你所知，这些机器在网络上都使用日志通道，
and maybe your client you know talking basically to the hardware,
也许你的客户端和硬件交互，
do the send a packet over the network,
通过网络发送数据包，
the actual hardware you know receive the packet,
实际的硬件会收到那个数据包，
and then that will and deliver it,
然后，它会发送它，
you know and the virtual machine monitor just gets control and delivers it,
虚拟机监视器获得控制权并发送它，
and hardware delivers to the virtual machine monitor,
硬件发送给虚拟机监视器，
virtual machine monitor will pick it up.
虚拟机监视器获得它。
And so, if you think about it,
所以，如果你仔细想想，
you know this, this package, you know results in, in an interrupt,
这个数据包结果是中断，
that deliver to the virtual machine monitor,
发送给虚拟机监控器，
the virtual machine monitor will send that interrupt,
虚拟机监视器将发送中断，
you'll see in a second,
你会在稍后看到，
and go forward to the backup,
然后发送给备机，
deliver it, deliver it also to the local virtual machine,
也将它发送给本地虚拟机。
the local virtual machine you know it's just Linux running,
本地虚拟机只是在运行 Linux ，
it saw I got an interrupt,
它看到我被中断了，
and so it does normal processing,
所以它会进行正常的处理，
it always will doing an interrupt,
它总是会处理中断，
and so at some point, you know maybe it will generate a response,
在某个时刻，它可能会产生回应，
and also for example write you know to the network card,
例如，可以写入网卡，
or at least it will think it's writing to the network interface card,
或者至少它认为写入网卡，
but really what it is, is a virtual network interface card,
但它实际上是一个虚拟网卡，
that is like emulated by the virtual machine monitor,
是由虚拟机监视器模拟的，
so when the writes actually you know a bunch of instructions to this you know virtual card,
所以，当写入很多指令到这个虚拟网卡时，
really what it is actually writing to the virtual machine monitor,
实际写入到虚拟机监视器，
and the virtual machine monitor seems like you know,
而虚拟机监控器会看到，
here's a operating system trying to actually send the packet,
这是操作系统想要发送数据包，
and then the virtual machine monitor can
然后，虚拟机监视器可以
actually send the packet away out of the operating system,
将数据包发送到操作系统之外，
by programming the real hardware,
通过对真实硬件进行编程，
and then the real hardware, it sends off in response to the client.
然后是真正的硬件发送响应给客户端。
Right, that has a normal execution,
这是一次正常的执行，
for what here's the primary, here's the backup,
这里是主机，这里是备机，
and basically the backup of the same thing happens,
基本上，在备机上也会发生同样的事，
you know if the machines started exactly in the same states,
如果机器在完全相同的状态下启动，
you know they take the interrupt you know at the same time,
它们同时接收中断，
and the virtual machine monitor control when to deliver the interrupt,
虚拟机监视器控制何时中断，
it can arrange to make sure,
它可以安排来确保，
that the interrupt to be delivered exactly at the same time,
中断在完全相同的时间发送，
exactly the same instruction, that the primary got it.
以主机得到的完全相同的指令（发送）。
So it will deliver the interrupt to the,
所以，它会将中断发送到，
you know will receive the interrupt from the primary,
将从主机接收到中断，
may be buffered for a while,
可能会缓冲一段时间，
until the backup machine second hits there's a same instruction the primary does,
直到备机随后得到主机同样的指令，
then delivers the interrupt the Linux,
然后将中断发送给 Linux ，
Linux is a usual way,
Linux 是一种常见的方式，
it will be,
它会，
you know since it's exactly the same state as in the primary,
因为它和主机的状态完全一样，
it will do exactly the same thing as the primary does,
它将与主机做完全相同的事情，
so at some point, you know it will,
在某个时刻，它会，
you know program virtual network card to actually send a response packet,
编程虚拟网卡发送响应数据包，
you know all that stuff will happen,
所有这些事情都会发生，
and at some points as like you know send a packet,
在某些情况下，发送一个数据包，
you know the virtual machine monitor will get control,
虚拟机监视器将获得控制，
it knows its backup
它知道自己的备机，
and so it doesn't do anything,
所以它什么也不做，
it actually doesn't send the packet on the network,
它并不会向网络上发送数据包，
because it's the backup.
因为这是备机。
Okay, that's the basic plan,
好的，这是基本的计划，
then there's one more component in this story,
然后，这个故事还有一个组成部分，
that is important to realize,
认识到这一点很重要，
which is that there is on the side, on the side,
那就是在一边，
on the machine network,
在机器网络上，
there is a storage server,
有一台存储服务器，
you can think about this as the hard disk,
你可以把它想象成硬盘，
for these for these two virtual machines or for,
对于这两个虚拟机，
and so when an application here writes to a file,
当应用程序写入文件时，
really what it turns into is you know the kernel will,
它会变成，内核将会，
you know that file systems may be mounted on the local Linux operating system,
文件系统可能会挂载在本地 Linux 操作系统上，
the Linux operating system sees this is a remote disk,
Linux 操作系统认为这是一个远程磁盘，
and will format the packet
将会格式化数据包，
and then will send a packet you know to,
并将数据包发送给，
you know, let me draw out maybe in a slightly different,
让我使用不同的颜色画一下，
will send a packet to the virtual machine monitor the same place,
将会发送数据包到虚拟机监视器，
and virtual machine monitor like send it off,
虚拟机监控器将它发送出去，
the virtual machine monitor you know go off,
虚拟机监视器发送，
and send it over network you know to the storage server,
通过网络将它发送到存储服务器，
the storage server will respond at some point,
存储服务器将在某个时刻响应，
in some ways this communication looks identical,
在某些方面，这种通信是一样的，
as if there's a client sitting on the other side of the network,
就像有一个客户端在网络的另一边，
the only difference being that,
唯一的区别是，
in the storage server case, the Linux starts the communication,
在存储服务器的情况下， Linux 启动通信，
while in other cases, the client starts the communication,
而在其他情况下，客户端启动通信，
green array represent communication to the storage server,
绿色箭头表示与存储服务器的通信，
so a network packets being sent
所以一个网络数据包发送
from through Linux, through virtual machine monitor to storage server.
通过 Linux ，再通过虚拟机监视器到存储服务器。
And so we write by an application to file,
所以，应用程序向文件写入，
basically results in these messages,
会导致这些消息，
and then it will whatever update any states,
然后更新任何状态，
you know persistent state, that you know on the on the storage server.
在存储服务器上持久化状态。
You know as we saw in the paper,
正如我们在论文中看到的，
the storage server plays an additional role,
存储服务器扮演一个额外的角色，
on top of, on top of basically being storate server,
在存储服务器的基础上，
namely, there's sort of a special flag that sits on the side,
也就是，这里有一个特殊的标志在旁边，
or there's a block in storage server,
或者在存储服务器上有一个块，
that's being used to arbitrate who becomes the primary after a failure.
它用来仲裁失败后谁将成为主机。
So, so this all comes down to,
所以，这一切都归结为，
this is the part of the failure over plan,
这是失败转移计划的一部分，
so let's see you know the logging channel breaks
所以，我们看看日志通道中断，
or in the way you know this manifest to the virtual machine monitor is that,
或者到虚拟机监视器的方法是，
it sends periodically packets you know over this logging channel,
它定期通过日志通道发送数据包，
and it doesn't get any responses from the other side,
而且它没有从另一边得到任何回应，
then assumes that the other side, there's a problem,
然后假设另一边，有一个问题，
and of course it can't decide,
当然，它不能决定，
whether you know just a network is not working,
只是网络不工作，
or whether actually the virtual machine monitor you know the computers really crashed.
或者是计算机真的崩溃了。
If it's really crashed,
如果它真的崩溃了，
of course, it should you know take over,
当然，你应该接手，
and if it's really not crash,
如果它没有真的崩溃，
then you know we have to arbitrate in some way,
那么我们需要某种方式来仲裁，
will make sure that only one of them actually proceeds.
确保他们中只有一个继续。
So let's say the network partitions,
让我们假设网络分区，
and so this is a harder case when the network partitions,
当网络分区时，这是一个更困难的情况，
instead of like one of them two crashes,
比起它们中的一个崩溃，
so here network partitions,
所以，这里发生网络分区，
but you know notice that the two could still communicate,
但是注意到这两个仍然可以通信，
both the primary and backup can communicate to the storage server.
主机和备机都可以与存储服务器通信。
And so in this particular case,
所以在这种特殊情况下，
what will happen is,
接下来会发生的是，
they will notice,
它们会注意到，
you know both sides will notice,
双方都会注意到，
the primary and backup will notice,
主机和备机将注意到，
there's some problems,
这里有些问题，
I can't talk to primary anymore [] [],
我不能与主机通信，
and so at some point to say,
所以在某种程度上，
well the other guy most probably could be dead,
另一个服务器很可能已经崩溃了，
and I want to promote myself to primary,
我想把自己提升为主机，
so the backup is like I want to promote myself to primary,
所以备机想把自己提升为主机，
or primary says like well I just want to really continue serving client request
或者主机说只想继续为客户端请求提供服务，
and I just want to ignore the backup for now.
现在只想忽略备机。
So basically says this is what they call they want to goes live,
这就是他们所说的继续存活，
basically we go back into single mode
我们会回到单一模式，
and we want to and we want one primary.
我们想要一个主机。
And so the way this happens is that,
所以，发生这种情况的方式是，
both of them you know send try to read,
它们两个都会试着读取，
they call test-and-set operation.
它们称为 test-and-set 操作。
I'll talk a little bit about it in more detail,
我会更详细地谈一谈，
but basically both reach out to the storage server,
但两者都连接到存储服务器，
and try to write a flag saying set to 1,
并试着写入一个标志，比如 1 ，
and if the flag was already set to set to 1,
如果该标志已经被设置为 1 ，
then it end,
然后就结束了，
like the the other guy 1 was earlier,
因为另一个写入 1 更早，
actually goes from 0 to 1.
从 0 到 1 。
They both try to do this atomically,
它们都试图以原子的方式来做这件事，
one is gonna go first,
其中一个首先完成，
you know that will succeed setting to 1,
将成功地设置为 1 ，
and we could return to old value 0,
我们可以返回到旧值 0 ，
so it knows that nobody else succeeded actually in writing to flat to 1 yet,
所以它知道没有其他人成功地写入 1 ，
and therefore I should become the primary to keep it running.
因此，我应该成为主机，让它继续运行。
And the second guy, you know what's the primary/backup,
主备的第二个，
you know that comes in second,
来的第二个服务器，
you know we'll see,
我们会看到，
we will try to set the flag to 1,
我们尝试将标志设置为 1 ，
is already set to 1,
已经设置为 1 ，
the return value would be 1,
返回值将是 1 ，
because that's the old value,
因为这是旧的值，
by the time you know did test-and-set operation,
当进行 test-and-set 操作时，
and therefore it will decide,
因此，它将决定，
well, I'm going to give up,
好的，我要放弃，
because you know there's already somebody else who took over for me,
因为已经有人接替我了，
and basically you know as the paper calls, you know they terminate itself.
正如论文中所说的，它们会终止自己。
Okay?
好的?
So that's sort of the high-level operation,
所以这是一种高级别的操作，
high-level operation failure.
故障高级操作。
There's a quick question in chat is a good question,
在聊天中有一个问题，是一个好问题，
and when is the flag reset to 0.
标志何时重置为 0 。
Well, there's sort of basically a whole separate story,
嗯，这是一个完全不同的故事，
that I'm talking about yet, you know see it get through,
我还在讨论，会逐渐看到，
is that once you know the primary runs,
就是一旦主机运行，
on when we have one server running now,
当我们有一个服务器运行时，
would like to make a second backup,
会做第二个备份，
you know and so get into position that we're basically having backup again,
所以我们又有一个备机，
we have to do what's called repair,
我们必须做修复，
because we don't do repair,
因为我们不做修复，
then you know the start with two computers,
那么从两台计算机开始，
one fails, then we have one computer,
一台计算机出现故障，我们就只有一台计算机，
and a little bit later,
然后过一会儿，
one computer may fail, then we have no computers anymore.
一台计算机可能出现故障，那么我们就没有计算机了。
So it has to be the case,
所以必须是这样，
there has to be a repair plan,
必须有一个修复方案，
and in VMFT, repair plan is executed manually,
在 VMFT 中，修复方案是人工执行的，
if somebody you know monitors, where monitor software sort of noticed this,
如果有人收到监控的通知，
and basically creates a new replica,
然后创建一个新的复制，
or based on the VM image of the the first one,
或者基于第一个虚拟机镜像，
ensures that in sync,
确保它们同步，
and then you know it reset that flag,
然后它会重置标志，
and you know in log log starts again,
当日志重新开始时，
and then the flag is reset,
然后标志会重置，
so once that second primary completely backup,
当第二个主机完成备份，
yeah and following the protocol, then the flag reset.
跟据协议，标志就重置了。
Okay?
好的?
Okay.
好的。
Okay, great, there's a great question,
好的，有一个好问题，
like why, you know may be logging channel broke,
比如可能日志通道中断，
that maybe the the the the channel to the server broke too,
可能通道到服务器也中断了，
and and so you know we're not gonna get a response,
所以我们不会得到回应，
and that basically that point the system just stops,
这就是系统停止的时刻，
if you will, until something repairs,
直到某些东西修复，
because nothing can be done,
因为什么都做不了，
so at that point from then on,
所以从那时起，
no clients request actually process,
没有客户端请求处理，
because we don't know what state we are,
因为我们不知道我们是什么状态，
and maybe at some point network link will get repaired,
也许在某个时刻，网络连接得到修复，
and that point things get started moving forward again,
那么事情又开始向前发展，
so this is a disaster case,
所以这是一个灾难案例，
where you know disaster case is,
灾难案例是，
actually the primary backup or both actually up and running,
主备都在运行，
but all the network cables broken.
但是所有网线都断了。
And which is sort of similar basically to the case,
与这个案例有些相似，
where both the primary backup failed at the same time.
主备同时失败的情况。
Okay.
好的。
Question, could you explain again real quick,
问题，你能再解释一遍吗，
when the client is reading from the storage server.
当客户端从存储服务器读取数据时。
The client never read really from the storage server,
客户端完全不从存储服务器读取数据，
that's the Linux that might,
可能是 Linux ，
or the application running on top of Linux
或者在 Linux 上运行的应用程序
might be running from the storage server,
可能从存储服务器运行，
and that's the one case.
这是一种情况。
And the second case,
第二种情况，
the VM-FT might be running from the storage server
VM-FT 可能从存储服务器运行，
to read that flag or test-and-set flag.
以读取 test-and-set 标志。
So that like green arrow at the bottom
所以底部的绿色箭头，
from the storage server to C, is a.
从存储服务器到 C ，是。
I'm sorry, that green, that's a bad green arrow,
抱歉，那个绿色的，是个错误的绿色箭头，
that should have gone all the way.
应该一直到这里的。
Okay, thank you.
好的，谢谢。
And just going over the network
只是通过网络，
and not intended to go to C,
并不打算去 C ，
it was intended to go over the network.
它是打算通过网络。
Thanks for clarifying that, and realize that.
谢谢你澄清这一点，认识到这一点。
Okay, so.
好的，所以。
So what I'd like, so I want to,
所以我想，
maybe if we take a quick break at this point,
也许我们可以中断一下，
or do a breakout room,
或者一个分组会议室，
in particular, would like you to do,
特别想请大家做的，
and talk a little bit about the homework question,
讨论一下家庭作业的问题，
which we sort of covered at this instance,
我们在这里谈到了，
but I want you to think about it,
但是我想你好好想想，
understand or argue with each other,
理解或互相讨论，
and you know convince yourself,
说服自己，
that the scheme actually provides avoids this sort of [],
这个方案避免了[]，
you know split-brain syndrome,
脑裂问题，
in the sense, that there's never going to be two primaries.
永远不会出现两个主机。
The second thing you know maybe to debate is,
第二件事要讨论的是，
this a reasonable design,
这是一个合理的设计，
because it looks like what we've done is,
因为看起来我们所做的是，
we put all the real hard part of fault tolerance into the storage server,
我们把真正的硬容错部分都放到了存储服务器中，
and it's not really the case,
事实并非如此，
why is that not the case.
为什么不是这样？
So that seems like two things that I'd like you to discuss,
所以这是我想让你们讨论的两件事，
in these breakout rooms.
在分组会议室里。
So I'm going to stop the sharing.
所以我要停止分享。
And I'm gonna, participants,
我要做的参与，
I'm gonna make Lily host,
我要让 Lily 来主持，
so that you can set up the breakout rooms,
这样你们可以设置分组会议室，
and you know enjoy talk to each other.
享受互相讨论。
Lily, you got this under control.
Lily ，控制权交给你了。
Testing to see if I can join a different room this time,
测试看看我能不能加入不同的房间，
it's not looking good though.
情况看起来并不乐观。
Well, yes, I'm stuck here.
是的，我被困在这里了。
The screen again,
又是屏幕，
can everyone see my screen?
大家能看到我的屏幕吗？
Yes.
是的。
Okay, good.
好的，很好。
So I hope you had a good discussion,
所以我希望你们讨论得很愉快，
and hopefully get more new students in the class than you knew before.
希望班上有比以前更多的新学生。
And let's sort of proceed,
让我们继续，
talking a little bit about the the design of of the VMFT,
讨论一下 VM-FT 的设计，
and there's like summarize quickly, you know.
并且快速总结。
Sorry could you repeat like when the flag is reset to 0,
抱歉，您能重复一下标志是什么时候设置为 0 吗，
I feel like some of us might have missed explanation.
我觉得我们中的一些人可能错过了解释。
Okay, okay, so okay, good good good.
好的，很好。
Okay, so let me,
好的，让我，
okay, so here let's draw the picture again,
好的，让我们再画一遍，
it's sort of similar way,
这是类似的方式，
here's our primary with the VM, everything in it,
这是我们的主机虚拟机，所有东西都在其中，
here's the backup, with everything in it,
这是备机，以及里面的所有东西，
you know and just logging channel in between,
日志频道在中间，
you know connected to a storage server.
连接到一个存储服务器。
And you know one thing to think about this,
有一件事需要考虑一下，
that the storage servers to playing two roles,
存储服务器扮演两个角色，
so let's separate the two roles,
所以让我们把这两个角色分开，
one is you knwo to storage you know for,
一个是存储，
disk basically for you know the primary and backup,
用于主机和备机的磁盘，
when we could just split that,
我们可以拆分它们，
and attach the disk to the primary backup,
并将磁盘连接到主备机，
then where basically have the role here is really the arbitration server,
然后另一个角色是仲裁服务器，
and it has a flag,
它有一个标志，
and the flag was initially 0, right.
标志最初是 0 ，
And so now let's say,
所以现在假设，
there's a partition to primary backup
主备之间有一个分区，
can actually not talk to each other anymore,
不能再相互通信，
so they're going to talk to arbitration server,
所以它们要访问仲裁服务器，
basically to try to promote themselves to the single to go live,
试着提高自己作为单独存活的服务器，
and sort of do single server, server the client request.
作为单台服务器为客户端请求提供服务。
So they both send the packet to the test-and-set operation,
所以它们都将数据包发送到 test-and-set 操作，
one get 0 back,
一个得到 0 ，
the other get 1 back,
另一个得到 1 ，
one gets 1 back, knows that it was actually the second who tried,
得到 1 的知道它是第二个尝试的，
and then, and so the first one will succeed, and will go alive,
然后，第一个会成功，并继续存活，
so let's say this guy goes live,
所以让我们假设这个存活，
and this guy just disappears,
然后这个就消失了，
the virtual machine is terminate itself and is done,
虚拟机会自己终止，然后完成，
and so now the flag is set 1.
现在标志设置为 1 。
And of course now at this point,
当然，在这一点上，
there's no arbitration necessary more,
不再需要仲裁了，
because there's no secondary replica,
因为没有第二个复制，
there's no backup at all,
根本没有备机，
so really the question is like what happens next,
所以真正的问题是接下来会发生什么，
and in terms of repair,
在修复方面，
that has to be the case,
会是这种情况，
that the second backup, new backup is brought up to alive, correct,
第二个新的备机拉起存活，
and section 3.1 the paper talks about this in quite a bit of detail,
这篇论文的 3.1 节对此进行了详细的讨论，
and the way it works is that,
它的工作方式是，
you know on the user interface,
在用户接口上，
you know to the system, you know VMware motion,
对于系统来说， VMware VMotion ，
you're basically saying like,
你是在说，
hey I want to clone this primary,
嘿，我想复制这个主机，
and the clone operation basically,
复制操作会，
well, basically stop processing processing client,
停止处理客户端，
during cloning, the primary won't actually worried about,
在复制过程中，主机不需要担心，
the one system still running,
只有一个运行的系统，
one actually serve any client request,
一个服务于任何客户端请求，
the the VMotion thing makes them VM clone
VMotion 复制虚拟机，
and basically copies the state of this VM up to tho backup,
将虚拟机的状态复制到备机，
so here we have an identical copy of the backup, of the primary,
所以，这里我们有一个完全相同的主机的复制，
that becomes the backup,
它成为备机，
and so the state of the virtual machine is identical.
所以，虚拟机的状态是相同的。
Once you know the sort of cloning operations happened,
一旦发生了复制操作，
then it's free,
然后它可以自由地，
user user interface is free to set this guy back to 0 too,
用户接口也可以自由地将这个（标志）设置为 0 ，
client requests are still not being processed,
客户端请求仍未得到处理，
when that has actually happened,
当这种情况真的发生时，
then this system can go sort of live again,
这个系统就可以重新开始工作了，
but now with two machines, with a primary and a backup,
但现在有两台机器，一台主机，一台备机，
and the client requests are being processed,
并且处理客户端请求，
they are sent over the channel and etc etc,
它们通过通道发送，
so we're back in business.
所以我们又回到运行中。
So answer the question?
所以回答了你的问题吗？
I hope it does.
我希望是这样的。
If not, I'm happy to revisit this actually,
如果不是，我很乐意重温这一点，
and maybe at the end of the lecture is still confusing.
也许在讲座的最后仍然令人困惑。
Okay.
好的。
Okay good.
好的，很好。
Okay, I want to go back now
好的，现在我想回到
to sort of like the overall architecture of this system,
这个系统的整体架构，
now I want to dive in a little bit more,
现在我想更深入一点，
and talk you know we decided to think,
我们决定考虑，
you know this arbitration scheme allows you to at least point to split-brain syndrome,
这个仲裁方案至少可以让你指出脑裂问题，
but you know this sort of larger issue,
但这种更大的问题，
that if you know two machines are running,
如果有两台机器在运行，
you know, our goal is going to be,
我们的目标是，
basically behave like a single machine.
像一台机器一样运行。
So from the client perspective,
所以从客户的角度来看，
it should not be possible to really discern,
应该不可能辨别出，
or at least in a sort of demonstrate a bad way,
或者至少在某种程度上证明了这一点，
that we actually have two machines, right.
我们实际上有两台机器。
And so there's this big step back,
所以回退一步，
if we think at a very high level,
如果我们在非常高的级别考虑，
you know we have here primary,
这里我们有主机，
and it has you know like machine registers, the virtual machine registers,
它有虚拟机寄存器，
there's memory,
这里有内存，
and our basic plan is to sort of forward
我们的基本方案是，
to make sure that basically executes exactly the same instructions.
确保执行完全相同的指令。
Boom, boom, boom, here's our own,
砰，砰，砰，这是我们的，
here's backup, here's primary,
这是备机，这是主机，
and you know basically you know when the, when the primary,
基本上当主机，
so we started to map in the same state,
所以我们开始在相同的状态下映射，
and they start executing instructions,
然后它们开始执行指令，
like maybe the first instruction is inc,
例如，可能第一条指令是 inc ，
second instruction is dec,
第二条指令是 dec ，
you know third instruction is branch,
第三条指令是 branch ，
and if they start all in the same state, correct,
如果它们都是从相同的状态开始，
that will branch into the same direction,
它将 branch 向同一个方向，
and so maybe the branch to some instruction,
也许 branch 到一些指令，
and then we know whatever the next instruction is divide etc, etc.
然后比如下一条指令是 divide 等等。
You know all these instructions are deterministic,
所有这些指令都是确定性的，
so that's pretty straightforward, right,
所以这是非常直截了当的，
like if you know we both start at the same state,
比如如果我们都是从同一个状态开始，
they execute exactly the same set of instructions in the same order,
它们以相同的顺序执行完全相同的指令集，
then we're going to end up in state S',
然后我们到达状态 S' ，
and those two states have to be identical, right.
这两个状态肯定是相同的。
Now the thing that is sort of a challenge in design,
现在，在设计中遇到的挑战是，
where any sort of replication scheme is,
任何种类的复制方案都是，
there might be sources of divergence,
可能会有差异来源，
you know so our goal is to actually get them exactly the same state S',
我们的目标是让它们完全一样的状态 S' ，
but you know there source or sources of divergence.
但是会有差异来源。
And it's pretty obvious, correct, what those are,
这是很明显的，
for example instructions that are non-deterministic our problems,
例如，不确定的指令就是我们的问题，
and so what are one example of non-deterministic instruction?
那么非确定性指令的例子是什么？
Getting the time.
获取时间。
Yeah, getting the time, why is it non-deterministic?
是的，获取时间，为什么它是不确定的？
Because it didn't,
因为它没有，
and the machines are not like the backup is not executing.
比如备机没有执行。
Yeah the issue here correctly is that,
是的，这里的问题是，
if there's the primary and the backup,
如果有主机和备机，
you know at some point will execute this you know get time of day instruction,
在某一时刻，会执行这个获取时间的指令，
if you will,
如果你愿意，
and they might not execute it exactly at the same time,
它们可能不在同一时间执行，
so the values returned by the instruction is going to be different, right,
所以指令返回的值将会不同，
so that's a source of, the potential source of divergence,
所以，这是可能的差异来源，
that we need to control.
我们需要控制的。
In fact,
事实上，
we basically have to turn every non-deterministic instruction into a deterministic instruction,
我们要把每一条非确定性指令变成确定性指令，
we'll see in a second and how, how could that be done.
我们稍后会看到如何做到这一点。
Similarly, inputs, packet inputs,
同样，数据包输入，
like when packet the arrives over the network,
例如当数据包通过网络到达时，
you know the primary,
你知道主机，
you know we got to make sure,
我们必须确保，
that you know the that packets executed or processed,
数据包执行或处理，
the interrupt goes along with that packet is exactly delivered
数据包带来的中断传送
exactly the same point in the instruction stream, right.
与指令流中完全相同。
So we go back to our previous paper, at previous page,
所以，我们回到上一页，
and like the backup is also executing these instructions,
备机也会执行这些指令，
and dec, blah blah blah,
和 dec 等等，
exactly the same order,
完全相同的顺序，
so if the primary for example,
所以如果主机，
you know we get the interrupt is delivered between instruction 1 2,
我们得到中断传送在指令 1 2 之间，
we've got to make sure that,
我们必须确保，
the backup it also delivered between 1 and 2,
备机也在 1 和 2 之间传送，
because it really delivered exactly the same point in the instruction stream,
因为它在指令流中以相同方式传送，
the interrupt handler will run and will do this,
中断处理程序将运行，
they both execute the same instructions again.
它们都会再次执行相同的指令。
However, if you know for example the backup you know would process
不过，备机会执行
this timer interrupt or is packet arrival interrupt
这个时钟中断或数据包到达中断，
a little bit later in a different side of stream,
稍晚一些在另一个流中（执行），
then the state of the system might be different,
然后系统的状态可能会有所不同，
and therefore the result of you know computation might be different,
所以计算结果可能会有所不同，
so we can't have that,
所以我们不能这样，
so it has to be the case,
所以，它必须是，
that interrupts whatever packets and timers all get delivered exactly at the same time,
数据包或时钟中断都会同时传送，
for the same input in the instruction stream,
与指令流的输入一样，
so input packets or timer interrupts,
所以输入数据包或计时器中断，
need to basically be delivered at the same point in the instruction stream.
需要在指令流中的同一点上传送。
And so those are sources of divergence,
所以这些都是差异的来源，
that we need to handle,
我们需要处理的，
any other source of divergence that?
还有其他差异来源吗？
So I think, like I think it was mentioned in the paper,
所以我想论文中提到过，
that concurrency also can produce non-determinism,
并发也会产生非确定性，
but from my understanding here,
但据我所知，
since the hypervisor actually controls the interrupts,
由于管理程序控制中断，
and since we have a unique processor,
因为我们有单独的处理器，
wouldn't the thread switch be conducted to the hypervisor by by interrupts,
线程切换不是管理程序通过中断进行的吗，
so if we control the interrupts,
所以如果我们控制中断，
and we can transmit them exactly at the right location,
我们可以准确地将它们传输到正确的位置，
wouldn't we also control the non-determinism from concurrency.
我们不是也可以控制并发的非确定性吗？
Yeah, so I think there's a great observation,
是的，我认为这是一个很好的观察，
so let me,
所以让我来，
it's a potential diverge,
这是一种可能的差异，
okay, so first of all,
好的，首先，
let's first agree that it's a potential source of divergence,
让我们首先同意这是一个可能的差异来源，
so multicore.
多核。
And let's see,
我们看到，
you know basically the way the solution in this particular paper
这篇论文中的解决方案，
to avoid this problem is to say,
避免这个问题是，
well, there's disallow, we're not allow to have that,
这是不允许的，不允许有（多核），
and so just only uniq processor,
所以，只有单个处理器，
let's say we had multi-core,
假设我们有多核，
and you know what just to make sure that we understand what the issue is,
为了确保我们了解问题所在，
the issue here is correct,
这里的问题是，
we have two threads running on the same processor,
我们有两个线程在同一处理器上运行，
sort of on different cores,
在不同的核心上，
and they arranged for example to grab grab a lock,
它们抢夺一把锁，
and one of them is going to win,
它们中的一个会赢，
and so that's the thread that's going to run next,
这就是接下来要运行的线程，
and the other one is going to be stopped for a little while,
而另一个会暂停一段时间，
if we want to do this replicated state machine approach at the backup,
如果我们想要在备机执行这种复制状态机方法，
the same thing would have to happen, right,
同样的事情也必须发生，
where if the two threads run, you know race for that lock at the same time,
如果两个线程运行，同时争夺锁，
then we got to be arrange that whatever winner on the primary,
然后我们必须安排在主机的胜者，
also the winner on the backup.
也是备机的胜者。
And so that requires a whole bunch of machinery,
所以，这需要很多机制，
that you know additional machinery complexities,
额外的机制复杂性，
that you know the paper clearly didn't want to address
这篇论文显然不想处理，
or didn't know how to address,
或者不知道该如何处理，
and basically just said, like,
只是说，
okay, we're just gonna exclude that possibility of divergence,
好的，我们只是排除这种差异的可能性，
but just declaring that the processor uni-processor.
只是宣布处理器为单处理器。
And so then thread switching and all that kind of stuff doesn't matter anymore,
然后线程切换和诸如此类的事情就不再重要了，
there's always one you know computation running on the computer, on the processor,
总是一种计算在计算机、处理器上运行，
and it will switch,
它会切换，
if the primary switches to a different thread,
如果主机切换到不同的线程，
the backup switch also to the same different thread,
备机也会切换到不同的线程，
because it's a single [instruction],
因为这是单一的指令，
and they get their external inputs exactly at the same time.
它们同时获得外部输入。
That makes sense?
这能理解吗?
So in some ways a little bit lame,
所以在某些方面有点差劲，
they just give up on multi-core.
他们放弃了多核。
And as I mentioned later systems,
正如我提到的，后来的系统，
in the more recent systems of this product, do handle multi-core.
在这个产品的较新系统中，可以处理多核。
And you know and yeah I want to talk to,
我想讨论一下，
I don't actually understand exactly how they do it,
我并不完全知道他们是如何做到的，
potential difference potential difference schemes,
可能是不同的方案，
that you could think of doing,
你可以想到去做的事情，
people have gone multi-core replay,
人们进行了多核重播，
which I really want the thing that is necessary,
我想是一件必要的事情，
so, but I don't really know exactly,
但我也不是很清楚，
I'm not gonna talk about that at all,
我不会再谈论这个，
I'm just gonna talk about that focus on the first three items,
我只想把重点放在前三项上，
and see how they handle it in this case.
看看他们在这件事上，是怎么处理的。
Okay, any questions?
好的，有什么问题吗？
Oh, sorry, just make sure,
哦，抱歉，只是确认一下，
it only transmits the instructions that the the application makes, right,
它只传输应用程序发出的指令，
it doesn't transmit the instructions that Linux makes.
它不会传输 Linux 生成的指令。
Yeah, exactly,
是的，没错，
so here's interesting thing we'll see in a second,
这是我们接下来会看到的有趣的事情，
but let me make it more clear right away,
但让我现在说得更清楚，
the, in fact, these instructions inc dec branch
实际上，这些指令 inc dec branch
are not sent to the primary backup at all,
不会发送到主机或备机，
they basically have their own copy, right,
它们都有自己的复制，
and we're just starting them at the same point in the program,
我们只是在程序中的同一时间点启动它们，
and so therefore they run exactly the sort of lockstep,
所以，它们的运行完全是步调一致的，
almost there's [no] one running lockstep,
几乎没有步调一致，
but they execute them in the same order,
但它们以相同的顺序执行这些命令，
only something special has to happen
只有发生一些特殊的事情，
at these points of diversion possible divergence,
在那些可能的差异点上，
and you know the assumption that sort of paper makes,
这篇论文假设，
the most instructions are deterministic,
大多数指令都是确定性的，
so we don't really have to do anything,
所以我们不需要做什么事情，
it's only the instructions were things that could potentially go wrong,
只有可能出错的指令，
we have to do something.
我们得做点什么。
And so one of those sources where something could go wrong is interrupts.
可能出现问题的来源之一就是中断。
So let's talk a little bit about interrupts.
所以，让我们来谈谈中断的问题。
And so here basically the virtual machine sort comes to
所以，这里虚拟机用来
rescue and really helps solve this problem,
修复和解决这个问题，
so let's say here we have our hypervisor,
我们假设这里有虚拟机管理程序，
and interrupt happens,
中断发生时，
that the interrupt will show up at the hypervisor,
中断将出现在管理程序中，
and the hypervisor knows exactly at,
并且管理程序确切地知道，
what instruction the application was
应用程序在什么指令上，
or where the VM was at this level,
或在这种级别上，虚拟机（在什么指令上），
so here Linux running inside of this VM,
这里， Linux 在这个虚拟机中运行，
the interrupt happens,
中断发生，
of course you know the the the hypervisor already has taken over control,
当然管理程序已经接管了控制权，
and it knows where it stopped you know Linux to actually take the interrupt.
它知道在什么地方停止 Linux ，以接受中断。
So maybe you know whatever it took it,
也许执行它，
it has executed a hundred instruction so far,
到目前为止，它已经执行了 100 条指令，
and then this interrupt comes in,
然后这个中断进来了，
and the hypervisor that wants to
管理程序想要
deliver that interrupt basically instruction after 100,
传递中断在 100 指令之后，
and before doing that actually,
在此之前，
it just sends over the logging channel,
它只是通过记录通道发送，
a message you know to the backup,
一条信息给备机，
so here's backup FT,
这是备机 FT ，
and in that message,
在那条消息中，
it basically says like okay at instruction 100,
它会说在指令 100 ，
you know when you get the instruction 100,
当你到达指令 100 时，
you know delivered this interrupt,
传递这个中断，
and maybe some data associated with the interrupt.
以及可能与该中断相关的一些数据。
So this is just two things interrupt comes in,
所以这是两件中断发生的事情，
sees what the instruction number was,
查看指令号是多少，
and then it sends to backup this message,
然后给备份发送这条消息，
saying like hey you know at some point,
说，在某个时候，
when you get to instruction 100,
当你到了指令 100 ，
you know process you know this interrupt.
执行这个中断。
And you know some point later, this interrupt 1 and interrupt 2 comes in,
过了一会儿，中断 1 和中断 2 进来，
and so then the hypervisor exactly the same thing you know again,
管理程序又是完全相同的事情，
they'll send out, say this is instruction 200,
它们会发出这是指令 200 ，
you know will send a message 200 interrupt,
可能发送一条消息 200 中断，
perhaps and any data associated the interrupt to the FT.
以及任何与中断有关的数据到 FT ，
So when you know the backup gets the first message,
所以，当备机收到第一条消息时，
just buffers the message,
只需缓冲消息，
because it doesn't know how long it can run after that message,
因为它不知道在这条消息之后会运行多长时间，
until it knows what the next point is that it has to deliver something.
直到它知道下一步必须交付一些东西。
So at the point that the second message comes in,
所以在第二条消息进来的时候，
you know for the second interrupt,
对于第二次中断，
it knows you know it's perfectly fine to start a computer,
启动一台计算机是完全正常的，
and instruction 100 delivered to interrupt,
指令 100 传送中断，
and basically keep running into instruction 200.
并且继续运行到指令 200 。
And the way it does,
它说做的方式，
it is basically most processors have this,
大多数处理器都有这个，
but x86 has this too,
x86 也有这个，
where you can basically program the x86
你可以对 x86 进行编程，
and say well you should stop after executing 100 instruction,
表示你应该在执行 100 指令后停止，
so the processor will stop where executing after 100 instructions,
所以，处理器会在执行 100 条指令后停止，
and this give back control to the operating system,
将控制权交还给操作系统，
in this case, the virtual machine monitor.
在这种情况下，就是虚拟机监视器。
And so you know so this is the scheme,
所以，这是我们的方案，
this is a scheme that VM-FT uses
这是 VM-FT 使用的方案，
to basically you know deliver interrupts,
用来传递中断，
both at the primary and the backup,
在主机和备机上，
exactly at the same instruction,
完全按照同样的指令，
so that they sort of stay in exactly
这样它们完全相同，
execute the instructions exactly the same order.
按照相同的顺序执行指令。
To arrange this,
要安排这一点，
of course going to backup which needs lag behind one, lag behind one message.
当然备机会落后一条消息。
Okay?
好的?
So just to be clear,
所以我只想确认，
so the deterministic operations don't
确定性操作不会
don't get communicated through the logging channel,
不会通过日志通道进行通信，
it's only the operations that perhaps might diverged.
只是可能出现差异的操作。
Exactly.
没错。
Usually got.
通常都是这样。
Exactly, what it does,
确实是这样做的，
so let's look at one more actually get the flavor,
所以让我们再来看看[]，
then we'll talk.
然后我们再讨论。
Yeah, go ahead.
好的，继续。
Sorry, so deterministic operations,
抱歉，所以确定性操作，
is that don't get communicated through the logging channel.
不需要通过日志通道吗？
No, there's no need for them,
是的，它们不需要，
because both of them of course have a copy of all the instructions,
因为它们都有一份所有指令的复制，
like the binary that, like whatever Linux runs, correct,
比如二进制，比如 Linux 运行的任何东西，
but you know the instructions are not communicated over logging channel,
但是指令不是通过日志通道通信的，
only the non-deterministic wants.
只有非确定性的（指令）需要。
So like in this interrupt and we'll see in a second,
就像这个中断，我们一会儿会看到，
here let's talk about the second one, non-deterministic instructions,
这里我们来谈谈第二个问题，非确定性指令，
like you get the timer, get timer of day.
比如定时器。
So the way that works is,
所以工作的方式是，
so here's we got our Linux running in the VM,
这里我们有 Linux 在虚拟机上运行，
we got our FT running,
我们有 FT 运行，
and basically when you know this Linux use a image,
这个 Linux 使用一个镜像，
program image that Linux runs,
Linux 运行的程序镜像，
and maybe you know here's are non-deterministic instruction,
也许这里有一些非确定性的指令，
and basically what FT has done,
基本上 FT 所做的，
before it started Linux,
在启动 Linux 之前，
you sort of gone through the Linux binary
你浏览 Linux 二进制文件，
and found all the instruction that the non-deterministic,
找到所有不确定的指令，
like get time of day,
比如获取时间，
and basically ensure you know turn them in sort of invalid instruction,
确保把它们转为无效指令，
and so when Linux execute, executes that non-deterministic instruction,
所以当 Linux 执行这些非确定性指令时，
it actually controls transfers control to the hypervisor,
它将控制权交给管理程序，
this is the trap.
这就是 trap 。
And now the hypervisor knows,
现在监控程序知道，
okay, well this was whatever instruction 341,
好的，这是指令 341 ，
I know that is a non-deterministic instruction,
我知道这是一个非确定性指令，
because I wrote you know those bits you know that caused the trap,
因为我写了导致 trap 的位，
and it will emulate that instruction,
它会模拟这条指令，
and so it will do all the effects that instruction has,
所以，它会实现执行的所有效果，
but record what the results of the effects are,
但是记录下效果的结果，
so for example, you know whatever we record what the result execution instruction,
例如，我们记录下执行指令结果，
the result stays goes into a0,
结果放到 a0 ，
it records the value a0
它记录值 a0 ，
and then basically sends to the backup,
然后发送到备机，
you know the outcome you know of that instruction,
那个指令的输出，
so whatever its value in a0 is whatever 221,
比如它在 a0 中的值是 221 ，
then of all you know send back,
然后所有发送回，
you know saying you know there's non-deterministic instruction,
表示有不确定的指令，
result of it is 221,
它的结果是 221 ，
and at some point, correct,
在某个时刻，
you know the backup legs behind,
备机是落后的，
it will you know execute,
它会执行，
because it's executing these instructions in the same order, in the same way,
因为它以相同的顺序，以相同的方式执行这些指令，
it will also execute the non-deterministic instruction,
它也会执行非确定性指令，
that will trap into the kernel,
会 trap 到内核，
and that usually wait
这通常会等待，
until you know since legs behind,
因为落后，
the already receives probably the message
直到收到消息，
and basically make sure that it sticks the same value,
确保它使用相同的值，
you know returns the same value as it did on the primary, right.
返回与主机上的相同的值。
So this is how non-deterministic instructions are handled.
所以，这就是非确定性指令的处理方式。
Sorry, so that happens,
抱歉，这种情况发生在，
like the modification of the binary,
比如修改二进制文件，
it happens when it creates the virtual machines?
发生在当它创建虚拟机时？
Yeah, we think about it, when it to boot to the VM.
是的，我们认为是在引导虚拟机的时候。
Okay.
好的。
But so the the backup re-executes the non-deterministic instruction,
但是备机重新执行非确定性指令，
and then just verifies the result?
然后只是验证结果？
No, what it actually does is,
不，它实际上做的是，
if the virtual machine monitor executes the instruction,
如果虚拟机监视器执行该指令，
and then you know,
然后你知道，
actually virtual machine monitor that doesn't execute instruction at all,
虚拟机监视器根本不会执行该指令，
it knows that this instruction needs to be executed,
它知道需要执行这个指令，
and it knows what things will be changed,
它知道事情会发生什么变化，
like what registers need to be updated,
比如哪些寄存器需要更新，
as a result of this instruction,
作为这个指令的结果，
and it sticks the value from the message into the register,
它将消息中的值放到寄存器中，
so that the Linux running on the backups
所以，在备机上运行的 Linux
is exactly the same effect as a Linux running on the primary.
与主机上运行的 Linux 的效果完全相同。
And so like this assumes that the hypervisor will do some work before
所以，这样假设管理程序事先做一些工作，
even or while putting up VM
在启动虚拟机之前，
just where the locations of these non-deterministic.
找出这些不确定（指令）的位置。
Yeah that with hypervisor does these [].
是的，管理程序执行这些[]。
So this is a standard hypervisor stuff,
所以这是一个标准的管理程序，
there's nothing new to FT,
对于 FT 没有什么新的，
other than these guys a ton of experience do hypervisor,
除了这些人拥有丰富的管理程序经验，
because VMware,
因为 VMware ，
and so they understand like what what it takes,
所以他们明白这需要什么，
and which instructions are non-deterministic.
以及哪些指令是非确定性的。
Okay, so.
好的，所以。
I I had one more, one more question,
我还有一个问题，
so if you know it's a program of fully like deterministic instructions,
如果这是一个完全确定性指令的程序，
could, could the backup run faster than the primary.
备机能不能比主机运行得更快。
Okay, so you know there's a whole discussion in the paper
好的，论文中有一个完整的讨论，
about like the speed of the primary and backup,
关于主备的速度，
and making sure that run roughly at the same speed,
确保它们以大致相同的速度运行，
because you don't want to get one far ahead and one far behind,
因为你不想领先太多或落后太多，
I think you should think about them,
我认为你应该考虑，
they're running on the sort of identical hardware,
它们在相同的硬件上运行，
and so they're running roughly at the same speed.
所以它们以大致相同的速度运行。
It's also the case that,
事实也是这样的，
there's going to be always some communication over this channel,
在这个通道上总会有一些通信，
because interrupts are happening periodically, right,
因为中断是周期性发生的，
like every you know whatever you know a couple of milliseconds,
比如每几毫秒，
or maybe a hundred milliseconds or ten milliseconds,
或者可能是一百毫秒或十毫秒，
depending on how Linux what rate Linux program the hardware timer,
根据 Linux 编程硬件定时器的速率，
there will be a timer interrupt,
会有一个定时器中断，
and timer interrupt will be propagated to the backup,
定时器中断会传送到备机，
and sort of be sync points if you want.
如果你愿意，也可以说是同步点。
Right, but my question is like,
是的，但我的问题是，
for example say you have a bunch of deterministic instructions, right,
比如，你有一堆确定性的指令，
instructions that are sent through the logging channel,
通过日志通道发送指令，
which means you know the primary and backup
这意味着主机和备机
can run those instructions at at their own pace, correct.
可以按照自己的速度运行这些指令，对吗？
Yes.
是的。
So, say what I mean,
所以，我的意思是，
I don't know if this could happen,
我不知道这是否会发生，
but say like it's you know a 100 instructions,
但是比如 100 条指令，
and the primary goes to like instruction 50
并且主机转到指令 50 ，
and gets gets a timer interrupt,
并获得定时器中断，
but the backup is already a timer like 60 or something,
但是备机已经是 60 的定时器了，
could could that.
这有可能吗。
It could not happen, right,
这是不可能的，
because remember the backup legs behind one of these messages.
因为记得备机落后一个消息。
So the backup won't start executing the next log until the primary has finished.
所以，在主机完成之前，备机不会开始执行下一个日志。
Okay.
好的。
This is why this is why it lags behind one.
这就是为什么它落后一个（消息）。
Like, to ensure that the backup is like lagging behind one instruction,
确认备份落后一条指令，
that does that mean.
这就意味着。
No not one instruction, one message on the channel.
不，不是一条指令，是通道上的一条消息。
But the interrupt is [interrupt], right,
但中断是中断，
so if we have,
所以，如果我们有，
as you said, if we have a hundred lines of instructions,
如你所说，如果我们有 100 行指令，
and running on the backup as well as the primary, then.
然后在备份和主机上运行。
The primary backup would not have started yet, right,
备机还不会开始，
so the primary runs 200 instructions,
所以主机运行 200 条指令，
the backup actually wait
备机会等待，
until the primary actually just completed whatever those 100 instructions,
直到主机完成这 100 条指令，
before it starts running those 100 instructions.
在它开始运行这 100 条指令之前。
So just one way to think about,
所以有一种方式可以考虑，
it always runs like one epoch behind.
它总是落后了一个时期。
Oh, so it's kind of a batching kind of scheme.
哦，所以这是一种分批计划。
Yeah.
是的。
Alright, thank you.
好的，谢谢。
Okay, so I want to talk a little bit about failure over,
好的，我想谈一谈关于失败的问题，
because there's a couple interesting,
因为有几件有趣的事，
there's one more rule that needs to be ensured,
还有一条规则需要确保，
that we actually get the right behavior.
我们得到正确的行为。
And so, so let's walk through some scenarios,
所以，让我们来看看一些场景，
here's the primary,
这是主机，
here's our hypervisor correct FT,
这是我们的管理程序 FT ，
here's our logging channel, FT,
这是我们的日志通道 FT ，
you know they both on the network,
它们都在网络上，
here's a client,
这里有一个客户端，
and here's our backup.
这是我们的备机。
And I'm going to talk about a couple of scenarios,
接下来我要讲几个场景，
so the first scenario are the normal case,
所以第一种情况是正常的情况，
a client sends a message you know to the primary,
客户端向主机发送消息，
where the servers running on the primary,
在主机上运行的服务器，
you know that's delivered of course to the primary,
当然是送到主机的，
also sent you know to on the channel.
也在通道上发送。
And let's assume for a second,
让我们假设一下，
that actually the message you know arrives you know at the hypervisor,
消息到达了管理程序，
so it actually knows that this was an interrupt,
所以它知道这是一个中断，
some packet arrived,
一些数据包到达，
and so now let's say the primary who sent a response back,
所以现在让我们假设主机发回响应，
and at that point, the computer crashes,
在这个时刻，计算机崩溃了，
so the primary fails,
所以主机出现故障，
the client has not gotten a response yet.
客户端尚未收到响应。
Now, this turns out to work out perfectly fine,
现在，这是非常好的，
because before you know the backup actually takes over,
因为在备机真正接管之前，
it first processes all it's message that has received yet,
它首先处理所有收到的消息，
because lags one behind, as we talked before,
因为像我们之前说的，落后一个（消息），
so you know this thing will be delivery.
所以这个东西是要传送。
So it will, sorry.
它会，抱歉。
Okay, let me a little bit more careful,
好的，让我再小心一点，
okay, so it gets delivered to the primary backup does it,
好的，它被传送到主备机，
but it actually won't send any response,
但它不会发出任何回应，
because it's still,
因为它仍然，
so you know doing exactly what the primary has done,
做主机所做的事情，
gets through that particular point and stops.
通过那个点，然后停下来。
Then point you know []
然后那个点[]，
you know or like the backup becomes the primary,
或者备机成为主机，
you know through the arbitration server,
通过仲裁服务器，
and the client will just timeout and retry,
客户端将会超时并重试，
because like TCP packet, then get a response,
因为就像 TCP 包，然后得到响应，
so retry actually trying to work out perfect.
所以重试把事情做得完美。
The interesting case is,
有趣的案例是，
what happens in the following scenario,
在以下情况下会发生什么，
where the client sends a request,
客户端发送请求的情况下，
it can it arrives at the primary,
它可以到达主机，
primary does the operation,
主机进行操作，
or whatever process the client request,
或者客户端请求的任何流程，
since the message to fault tolerance server,
因为消息是给容错服务器的，
in the meantime,
与此同时，
okay, it was also sent on the logging channel,
好的，它也会发送给日志通道，
but let's say we got unlucky,
但是假设我们运气不好，
and the message actually never made it over the logging channel,
这条消息从未通过日志通道，
and,
同时，
but the primary actually you know sends a response,
但是主机发送响应，
before just sends a response and then it fails, right,
在发送响应之前，然后它失败了，
and so for example like,
比如，
maybe you know this request was to increase the variable from 10 to 11,
可能这个请求是将变量从 10 增加到 11 ，
so inc the old state was 10 and now the new state is 11, right.
所以 inc ，旧的状态是 10 ，现在新的状态是 11 ，
And is this problematic, this scenario?
这种情况有问题吗？
Yeah, because when the backup takes over,
是的，因为当备机接手的时候，
it won't know about that increase,
它不知道这个增长，
and so it'll just continue execution as if it didn't happen,
所以，它将继续执行，就像它没有发生一样，
and this provides like inconsistent output
我想这会造成不一致的输出，
to the external like [facing] world I guess.
对于外部的世界。
Yeah, exactly, right,
是的，没错，
because the primary will takeover, the backup will take over,
因为备机将会接管，
the value still be 10,
而值仍是 10 ，
and now if the client does inc,
现在如果客户端执行 inc ，
it can actually gets 11 back,
它会得到 11 ，
instead of 10, instead of 12, right.
而不是 12 。
So this is no good,
所以这是不好的，
and so how is this avoided this problem?
那么如何避免这个问题呢？
The primary will send things to the backup
主机将数据发送到备机，
and then wait for acknowledgement,
然后等待确认，
and once that acknowledgement is received,
一旦接收到确认，
it can send output,
它可以发送输出，
and it doesn't matter whether the backup actually runs the command,
备机是否运行该命令并不重要，
it just has to have it,
它只是必须拥有它，
so that if it ever needs to take over as primary,
如果它需要接手主机的工作，
it has that and it's logs,
它有它的日志，
and it will catch up before actually like become primary.
在成为主机之前，它会赶上。
Exactly right, so this is what's called the output rule,
完全正确，这就是所谓的输出规则，
and the rule is that you know before you can output,
规则是在你可以输出之前，
you got to make sure that,
你必须确保，
the preceding messages that you were sent to the backup
前面发送给备机的消息，
actually have been received by the backup.
已经在备机接收到了。
So this scenario I just drew out going actually never happen,
所以我刚才提出的这个场景实际上不会发生，
because you know at that point,
因为在这一点上，
you know the primary wants to send a response out on the network,
主机想要在网络上发送响应，
the FT, the primary FT will wait
主机 FT 将会等待
until this message actually has has been received by the backup,
直到该消息已经被备机接收到，
and only when it received an acknowledgement from the backup FT,
并且仅当它从备机 FT 收到确认时，
and now knows you know that basically the backup has a copy of this input,
现在知道备机有一份这个输入的副本，
and so whatever you know whatever it fails,
所以不管它失败了，
you know the backup will you know process that input,
备机会执行那个输入，
and basically get a computer in the same state as the primary,
并且得到一台与主机处于相同状态的计算机，
so at that point and actually safe to send out the reply.
所以在这一时刻，发出回应是安全的。
And so this is the output rule,
这就是输出规则，
is that you don't output
就是你不会输出，
until all preceding messages that you send over log channel
直到前面所有你通过日志通道发送的消息
actually have been received by the backup.
已经被备机接收到。
And so just to clarify,
我想确认一下，
it seems that the output rule is here to solve the inconsistency,
看起来输出规则就是用来解决这种不一致的，
that could happen if we have some non-determinism,
如果我们有一些非确定性的，
so like let's say that we have the output operation to be instruction 60,
比如，我们的输出操作是指令 60 ，
and we do not have the output rule,
而且我们没有输出规则，
and so the backup actually did not,
所以备机实际上并没有，
let's say for some reason did not receive the output operation,
假设由于某种原因没有接收到输出操作，
or it did not receive up until the output operation,
或者直到输出操作才接收到，
if the instructions are deterministic between the point,
如果指令在点之间是确定性的，
where the backup did not receive messages
备机没有收到消息，
until the point where we have an output operation,
直到我们进行输出操作时，
do we still run into the problem of the inconsistency?
我们还会遇到不一致的问题吗？
Yeah, because the client might observe that, right,
是的，因为客户端可能会注意到这一点，
the client might have observed that actually value is now 11.
客户端可能会注意到现在的值是 11 。
And so when it actually talks to the backup after the primary has failed,
所以，当它在主机发生故障后，访问备机时，
you know then the value should only 10,
值应该只是 10 ，
and you know that can't be true,
那是不可能的，
so that you know that reveals that is not behaving like a single system.
这显示它的行为不像一个单一的系统。
I see.
我明白了。
It's the external thing you know the external client that will observe something wrong,
外部客户端会观察到一些错误，
and this is why the output rule exists,
这就是输出规则存在的原因，
in any replication system,
在任何复制系统中，
that we'll see this semester
我们在这学期会看到的，
has something like the output rule.
都有类似输出规则的东西。
And it turns out to be,
结果是，
you know for example you'll see in the, even in the raft paper,
比如，你会在 raft 论文中看到，
but also in the zookeeper,
也在 zookeeper 中，
there's sort of this notion,
有这样一种概念，
that you know sometimes you want to like respond to reads immediately,
有时你想直接回复读取，
but you can't really do that,
但你不能这么做，
because you run this risk
因为你冒着这种风险，
and sort of an equivalent of an output rule,
相当于一条输出规则，
that tries to avoid you know problems like like that.
试图避免像这样的问题。
So does the client re-execute the command,
因此客户端会重新执行该命令吗，
like do they get some sort of signal that,
比如它们会不会得到某种信号，
because the command was never ack by the backup.
因为备机从未确认过该命令。
Okay, okay so let's say we did not get the ack, right,
好的，我们假设没有收到确认，
so, I've got to backup but not to the ack,
所以，我回到备机没有确认，
then the client will not
那么客户端不会，
you know this response would have not been sent to the client yet, right,
这个响应还没有发送到客户端，
the backup will take over,
备机将会接管，
the client presumably will timeout,
客户端可能会超时，
and do whatever it needs to do,
做任何它需要做的事，
either you know does nothing,
要么什么都不做，
you know if you know that's part of their,
如果这是它们的一部分，
that's part of the protocol between servers and clients,
这是服务器和客户端之间协议的一部分，
most likely the client will re-send the TCP connection,
最有可能的是，客户端会重新发送 TCP 连接，
the response packet didn't get received,
没有收到响应包，
and so it will you know try to re-send,
所以它会试着重新发送，
and so it will re-send to backup,
所以它会重新发送到备机，
and then finish the operation,
然后完成操作，
but it won't observe an old value.
但它不会观察到旧的值。
Okay?
好的?
Okay, now I want to talk one thing a little bit,
好了，现在我想说一件事，
then so this system I think it's actually very cool,
所以我认为这个系统非常酷，
it's a very clean version of state machine replication,
这是一个非常清楚的状态机复制版本，
it brings out this issue of non-determinism,
它解决了非确定性的问题，
the issues like the output rule,
像输出规则这样的问题，
that we'll see in a version of that,
我们将在一个版本中看到，
we'll see a similar in in other systems,
我们将在其他系统中看到类似的情况，
but I want to talk a little bit about performance,
但我想谈一谈性能，
because like one downside of this system is,
因为这个系统的一个缺点是，
you know because you're doing things
因为你做事情
at the level of the machine instructions or level interrupts,
在机器指令或中断的级别上，
there you pay performance hit.
你会付出性能的代价。
So like 1 and 2 tables that are in the paper,
所以像论文中的表格 1 和 2 ，
and one the first thing to observe is that,
首先要观察的一件事是，
actually the left table is extremely good,
左边的表格非常好，
so the backup and the primary,
所以备机和主机，
you run the backup primary performance was very close to
运行备机和主机的性能非常接近于，
as if you were not running with a backup,
像没有使用备机运行，
which is very very impressive,
这非常令人印象深刻，
and in fact including the fact that you're running a virtual machine,
包括你运行的是一台虚拟机，
the more, the more troublesome part is this side of things,
更麻烦的部分是这边的事情，
where if you don't run in a primary/backup mode,
如果你不在主/备模式下运行，
you know like your bandwidth and receiving and sending actually pretty high,
比如你的带宽和收发相当高，
you know at least in the particular experiment they did.
至少在他们所做的实验中。
But you know when you're running the backup mode,
但是当你运行备机模式时，
things are actually not so good, right,
其实不是很好，
you know these numbers are quite different,
这些数字有很大的不同，
in fact like 30% reduction in performance.
事实上，性能下降了 30% 。
And where is that 30% coming from,
这 30% 是从哪里来的，
like why, why is that the case.
为什么会这样。
Because the primary is actually the one receiving inputs from outside.
因为主机是接受外部输入的。
Yeah, I think there's two cases,
是的，我想有两种情况，
in on receiving a case,
在接收的情况下，
where the primary receiving input from the outside,
主机接收来自外部的输入，
where does that need to go.
这需要放在哪里。
If you see a packet from the from the client,
如果你看到来自客户端的数据包，
so that packet has to be sent to the to the backup, sort of.
数据包必须发送到备机。
Wait, but the primary is also the one sending output back to the clients,
等等，但是主机也是将输出发送回客户端的服务器，
so is that what's using the bandwidth.
所以这就是使用带宽的原因。
Yeah, well, there's that one reason,
是的，这是一个原因，
but the real thing I think is going on here is that,
但我认为这里真正发生的事情是，
the primary has to wait
主机必须等待，
until it can send a response to a client
直到它可以向客户端发送响应，
until the backup actually has acknowledged it.
直到备份确认该响应。
And so just came like process packets,
所以处理数据包，
the same speed as good without actually backup.
可以获得没有备机相同的速度。
And therefore we should see a reduction in performance.
所以，我们会看到性能下降。
Nevertheless, this performance is pretty impressive,
尽管如此，性能还是相当令人印象深刻，
but you know there's a performance cost.
但这是有性能代价的。
And this is one reason,
这是一个原因，
that people play this game replicated state machines not at the instruction level,
人们不在指令层面上使用复制状态机，
but at the application level,
而是在应用程序级别，
and basically be able to get higher performance,
能够获得更高的性能，
but that requires modification to the applications,
但这需要修改应用程序，
as we saw in GFS.
就像我们在 GFS 中看到的那样。
Okay, I think I'm running a little bit over time,
好的，我想我有点超时了，
so I'm gonna stop right now,
所以我现在要停止了，
so I hope people that actually needed to leave already left,
所以我希望需要离开的人已经离开了，
but I'll stick around,
但我会留下来，
and see if people have more questions,
看大家有更多的问题，
I'll be happy to answer those.
我很乐意回答。
And I'll talk to you on Tuesday.
我周二再跟你们讨论。
Thank you.
谢谢。
I had a question about the previous image,
我对之前的图像有一个问题，
that you drew with, with the,
你画的那个，
yeah that one,
是的，就是那个，
I was confused because,
我很困惑，因为，
wasn't it the case that,
不是这种情况，
then we do an increment,
然后我们做一个增加，
we don't need to send anything to the backup right.
我们不需要发送任何东西给备机，对吗。
There, okay, so there's two things going on here,
好的，这里有两件事，
so we do see,
所以我们看到，
at the at the point that the message comes in,
在消息到达的时刻，
like this increment comes in from the client,
比如来自客户端的这个增加，
arrives at the FT at the hyper, the primary hypervisor,
到达主机管理程序的 FT ，
it needs to forward that message to the backup FT,
它需要将该消息转发到备机 FT ，
so that it can process,
这样它才能处理，
it needs to be processed when it needs to be processed,
当它需要处理的时候，
when it processes exactly the same point in this instruction stream, right.
它处理这个指令流中的完全相同的点。
So it sends it off,
所以它发送出去，
and then you know delivers it to the primary,
然后把它发送到主机，
and then the primary goes up and does its thing,
然后主机上线，做它自己的事情，
primary you know may respond with a message,
主机回复一个消息，
and so if the primary responds with a message,
所以，如果主机回复了一条消息，
the output of that message is stop
消息输出会停止，
or hold until the backup as acknowledged the reception of this increment,
或者直到备机确认这个增加的回复，
which will ensure that if the backup has to take over,
这将确保如果备机必须接管，
whatever it will process that increment first,
它会首先处理这个增加，
and it also will be 11 before response sent.
它也会是 11 ，在发送回复之前。
Okay, okay, thank you.
好的，好的，谢谢。
One thing I'm confused about is,
我搞不懂的一件事是，
is the goal of the system to to help with like bucking up an actual server,
系统的目标是帮助提高服务器的性能吗，
where because it's not easy to handle the interrupt without a hypervisor
因为在没有管理程序的情况下处理中断并不简单，
or is it actually to help distribute virtual machines themselves.
或者它是为了帮助分发虚拟机本身。
And it's purely to make an app,
它纯粹是为了让应用程序，
like you have a business application that runs on a single machine,
比如你有一个在一台机器上运行的业务应用程序，
and you want to make it more fault tolerance,
你想让它具有更强的容错性，
and the what this scheme does is,
而这一方案的作用是，
it makes it fault tolerance for you transparently,
它透明地为你提供容错功能，
you run the business applications and both machines on the on the FT hypervisor
你在 FT 虚拟机管理程序上运行业务应用程序和虚拟机，
and FT hypervisor will ensure that,
FT 管理程序将确保，
you know basically these applications more or less not literally running lockstep,
这些应用程序不是按字面意思同步运行，
but basically you know fault tolerance replicated.
基本上是容错复制的。
So the VM using the VM itself is kind of a design decision.
所以，使用虚拟机本身在某种程度上是一个设计决策。
Yes, and that is a good design decision,
是的，这是一个很好的设计决策，
because it allows you to do this replication at a transparent level.
因为它允许你在透明级别执行复制。
Got it, thanks so much.
明白了，非常感谢。
You're welcome.
不客气。
Yeah, the question in the chat,
是的，聊天中的问题，
about can be a the output rule,
关于输出规则，
is it possible that the client sees the same response twice.
客户端是否可能看到相同的响应两次。
And the answer is yes,
答案是肯定的，
it's absolutely possible,
这是可能的，
that the client will see you get the response twice,
客户端完全有可能收到两次回复，
and basically what they argue that's okay,
他们说是可以的，
because in sort of the fault tolerant model of the network,
因为在网络的容错模型中，
it is always assumed the network can actually duplicate messages anyway,
总是假设网络可能重复消息，
and so protocols like TCP are totally designed to deal with duplicate messages.
所以，像 TCP 这样的协议完全是为处理重复消息而设计的。
So yes, it's okay, because TCP,
所以，是的，因为 TCP ，
or whatever replication duplication scheme,
或任何复制方案，
the application uses, where the client uses.
应用程序使用，客户端使用的。
I was curious about [] question,
我对[]问题很好奇，
which is primary like sort of goes down for a few minutes,
比如主机停机了几分钟，
backup goes live,
备机开始运行，
then sets up its its own backup,
然后建立自己的备机，
you know switches the bit back to 0,
把标志位换回 0 ，
and then suddenly somehow the first primary goes back,
然后突然第一个主机又回来了，
like goes back.
比如，回来。
Yeah, I think we're going to have the case,
是的，我想我们会有这种情况，
that first primary is definitely terminated,
第一个主机肯定会被终止，
it's cleaned up and gone.
它被清理干净，然后就消失了。
Hmm, nice, thanks.
嗯，好的，谢谢。
To ask a question something similar,
问一个类似的问题，
may be too broad question,
可能是个过于宽泛的问题，
but like will you ever need to store more things
你是否需要保存更多东西，
besides an arbitration flag and the server,
除了仲裁标志和服务器之外，
I mean besides the flag an arbitration server,
我的意思是除了仲裁服务器标志位之外，
if you have like multiple like backups.
如果你有多个备机。
Oh yeah, like this is a scheme [] to at one backup,
是的，这是一个方案[]对于一个备机，
not more than one backup,
不会超过一个备机，
so if you had more backups,
所以如果你有更多的备机，
you know, you know, there's other issues that we need to resolve,
我们还有其他问题需要解决，
in fact we'll come back to this, on Tuesday,
事实上，我们将在周二回到这个问题上，
you know with more sophisticated protocols,
使用更复杂的协议，
that handle those cases much cleaner.
更干净地处理这些情况。
Okay, that was just perfect cool, thank you.
好的，这太酷了，谢谢。
I have one question about the performance,
我有一个关于性能的问题，
so can you go back to that table?
所以你能回到那个表格吗？
Yes, my question is,
好的，我的问题是，
is it the delay only be viewed on the first packet,
是不是只在第一个数据包上才能看到延迟，
like after the first packet,
在第一个数据包之后，
it will just flow through the channel,
它只会流过通道，
and there's no extra delay on the link,
链路上没有额外的延迟，
so the bandwidth should be roughly the same, or no.
所以，带宽应该大致相同，或者不是。
No, okay for every packet received correctly by the primary,
不是，对于主机接收到的每个数据包，
you know that packet has to be forwarded to the backup,
数据包必须被转发到备机，
for every response you know backup the left wait
对于每个响应，备机等待，
for the primary has to wait
主机必须等待，
until the output rule is satisfied,
直到满足输出规则，
then it can send a response.
然后它就可以发送响应。
So there's some lag processing on the backups,
所以在备机上会有一些延迟处理，
backup server to before getting back to the primary.
在返回到主机之前。
Yeah, so they talk a little bit about that, correctly,
是的，他们稍微讨论了一下，
the particular processing that needs to be done is,
需要完成的处理是，
actually acknowledging the reception of the packet on the logging channel.
确认在日志通道上数据包的接收。
And they talk a little bit about how to reduce the delay
他们还谈了一些如何减少延迟，
to make sure that sort of acknowledgment is very quick.
以确保这种确认是非常迅速的。
I see, I see okay, thank you.
我明白了，好的，谢谢。
I have a question about the logging channel,
我有一个关于日志通道的问题，
so they they mentioned that they use UDP,
所以他们提到他们使用的 UDP ，
and I assume that's mostly for performance,
我想这主要是为了性能，
but then so basically if a single failure happens, the primary,
但是，如果发生一次故障，
if a single packet is unacknowledged,
如果单个数据包未被确认，
then it assumes that the backup failed,
然后，它假设备机失败，
without any like retransmission.
没有任何重播。
No, no, yeah, because there's a timer interrupt,
不，不，是的，因为有计时器中断，
and the timer interrupt goes off like every ten milliseconds or something,
定时器中断大约每 10 毫秒或更长时间触发一次，
there's always multiple packet,
总是有多个数据包，
one packet sent,
发送一个数据包，
that packet doesn't get no heartbeat coming back,
那个数据包不会收到任何心跳，
then it will do a couple of these time interrupt,
然后它会中断几次这样的时间，
before it gives up.
在它放弃之前。
Okay, and the heartbeats, are they [] from the primary
好的，心跳是从主机开始[]的吗，
or it was going to apply it from somewhere else in the system.
或者它将从系统中的其他地方应用它。
Well, they sort of come from the timer,
好的，它们从某种程度上来说来自定时器，
when the heartbeat basically an indirect side effect,
心跳是间接的作用，
because every ten milliseconds,
因为每隔 10 毫秒，
you're gonna send an interrupt message to the over logging channel anyway.
你会通过日志通道发送一条中断消息。
I see, okay.
我明白了，好的。
Alright, thank you.
好的，谢谢。
You're welcome.
不用谢。
Actually I wanted to follow up on that,
我想要跟进这件事，
I think it said that it's gonna wait a couple a few seconds.
我想它说的是要等几秒钟。
Yeah, yeah, it can wait a while,
是的，可以等待一段时间，
you know they do a couple of heartbeats and wait a while,
他们会做几次心跳，然后等一段时间，
and if they're really, none of them come through,
如果没有一个能通过，
then it will stop.
然后它就会停止。
Okay, and is a few seconds that's a lot, right.
好的，几秒钟够多了吧。
I don't remember exactly all the numbers,
我记不清所有的数字了，
so you could be right in a few seconds,
所以可能是几秒钟，
I would imagine a bit shorter, but maybe it's not.
我想可能会短一点，但也许不是。
I think, I'd like something in the order of a few seconds,
我想几秒钟左右的东西，
but is it bad?
但它是坏的吗？
That much longer for the cloning,
复制的时间要更长，
but you know I can't remember it like.
但我记不起来了。